Warning! Decompression Hazard!
警告：减压危险
Come here! There's a... there's a fucking...
快来，快来人啊
Alert the fucking crew... there's a fucking passenger emergency in...
快他妈的通知机组
whatever the fucking place is!
管他妈的在什么地方
Complying. Correction, unable to comply. No crew on duty.
正在执行
No on duty crew? Is anybody out there? Hey!
没有机组人员执勤？
Wait. No. What the? They're dying!
等等，不！什么情况
Oh shit. Hey you in there! Wake up! Wake up!
完了，里面的人能听见吗
Unable to comply. Only on duty crew may initiate reanimation.
无法执行，只有当班机组人员才能启动复苏程序
You said there's no on duty crew on board! So guess what? I'm your fucking captain now!
你不是说没有执勤机组吗
Complying. Emergency passenger promotion for Lyra Scenic.
正在执行：乘客莱拉·西尼克已被紧急晋升
That probably should have been harder. Now, computer, open this pod before I...
这晋升怎么这么简单
Alert! Alert!
警报！警报！
Oh what is it now?
现在又咋了？
There is a fucking passenger emergency in container 801.
在801号舱有乘客出他妈的大事了
Just open the pod!
快给老娘打开舱门！
Complying. Correction, unable to comply. Service code 4879.
执行中，更正：无法执行，服务代码：4879
Hold on. I'm getting you out of there.
坚持住，我现在就把你救出来
Captain, pod 3 is now open.
船长，3号舱已打开
Oh shit.
他妈的
Wake up! Wake up! Wake up!
醒醒啊！醒醒啊！醒醒啊！
Yeah, yeah, yeah. What the hell?
嗯？嗯？嗯？发生什么事了？
You're... you're alive!
你……你竟然还活着！
Computer, alert the fucking crew! There's a fucking passenger emergency!
电脑，赶紧他妈的叫机组！
I tried that. We are on our own.
我已经试过了，现在我们只能靠自己了
I had to crack open your pod before it freeze-dried you.
我只能手动把你舱门弄开，不然你就凉透了
No wonder I feel like there's a solar flare in my skull.
怪不得我感觉脑袋里像有太阳耀斑在炸
There's a reason why defrosting usually takes 8 hours.
所以说，解冻通常得花8个小时，肯定是有道理的
You are not part of the crew, are you?
你不是机组成员吧？
Hell no. Name's Lyra. And I'm just a prisoner, like you.
锤子
Sorin?
索林？
Sorin Jax. How do you know my name?
索林·贾克斯，你怎么知道我的名字？
Well, it's on the screen.
屏幕上不是写着吗？
Oh yeah, sure.
哦，对，行吧
We have to find out what happened.
我们得搞清楚到底发生了什么
I'm pretty sure we weren't supposed to wake up like this.
我敢肯定，我们本不该以这种方式醒来
Something must have gone terribly wrong.
一定是哪里出了大问题
These pods are meant to have systems in place that keep us alive in an emergency.
这些冷冻舱应该会在紧急情况下
It should have properly reanimated us and opened the moment it switched to backup power.
按理说，它切换到备用电源时
Sounds like you know your way around spaceships.
听起来你很懂飞船的操作啊
Yeah, we're in an EZ-Trans container. Been hauling them around for a long time myself.
对啊，我们在EZ-Trans的集装箱里
It turns people into cargo. It's all self-contained.
它把人当成货物处理，一切都是独立运作的
It's basically the cheapest way to get around the system.
说白了，这是在星系里最省钱的交通方式
You worked a freighter?
你在货船上工作过？
Yeah, sort of. I used to fly one, to be precise.
嗯，算是吧
Any idea who's in this one?
你知道这里面是谁吗？
Only authorized crew may-
只有授权机组人员才可以——
Just open the damn pod, computer!
电脑，把这该死的舱门打开
Unable to comply. Service code 4879.
无法执行，服务代码：4879
Huh?
哈？
Your pod said the same.
你的舱也一样
Code 4879, that's a new one.
服务代码4879，这是个新的
Life support is all messed up. His body's gonna poison itself if we don't get him out.
维生系统彻底宕机了
Here, help me pull the lid.
过来，帮我把盖子拉开
No, no, no. Wait, wait, wait. Let me get up here.
不不不，等等，让我先上这边
These pods have an emergency release hatch right here.
这些舱在这儿有个紧急按钮
He... he's not moving.
他……他已经不动了
Do you know first aid?
你会急救吗？
Help me get him out.
帮我把他拉出来
Got him?
抓住他了吗？
Yeah, yeah. Got him.
好了，好了，抓住了
Okay, put him over there.
好，把他放到这边来
Quick, quick, quick, quick.
快快快
Okay.
好了
Huh.
嗯哼
There. No pulse. No breathing.
好了，没有脉搏，也没有呼吸
And he's almost frozen.
而且他几乎被冻僵了
Even if I knew how to do muzzle to beak, he's probably too far gone.
就算我知道怎么做人工呼吸，他大概也救不回来了
Damn.
造孽啊
So what the hell's going on here?
所以这里到底他妈的发生了啥？
I'm pretty sure we haven't made it to Vesta prison camp yet.
我很确定我们还没到维斯塔监狱呢
Computer, status report.
电脑，报告情况
Complying. Correction, unable to comply.
正在执行，更正，无法执行
I wouldn't trust the computer.
我就不该相信电脑
It promoted me to captain without putting up a fight.
它想都没想就把我升成了船长
Stay here and catch your breath.
先待这儿，休息一下
I'll try the door and check to...
我去试着开门，顺便检查一下……
No, no, no. Stop, stop, stop, stop, stop.
不不不，停下，停下
See the red light over there?
你看到那个红灯了吗
Red light means a hard vacuum on the other side of the airlock.
红灯亮着说明气闸另一边是真空
You're gonna kill yourself.
你真的是在作死
No need to shout at me, Sorin.
别对我大喊大叫，索林
It's my first time off world.
这是我第一次离开家园
Sorry, captain.
抱歉，船长
If I really were a captain, I would probably know what to do.
要真是我船长的话，我大概就知道该干啥了
Don't worry. There are procedures for emergencies like this.
别担心，这种紧急情况是有应对流程的
Take this suit you went to sleep in, for example.
拿你睡觉穿的这套衣服来说吧
It doubles as a space suit if you add a matching helmet.
配上相应的头盔就能当太空服用
There should be a box somewhere.
这边应该有个箱子的
Oh, right here.
嗷，在这里
I wouldn't want to go on an actual space walk in one of these, but...
我可不想穿着这玩意儿去太空行走，不过……
Well, you never know.
这可不好说
Oh.
完了
Oh, what?
什么完了
One of the helmets is already missing.
其中一个头盔已经不见了
The fourth pod!
第四个冷冻仓
It was already open when I woke up.
我醒来的时候，那个冷冻仓就已经打开了
Whoever woke up first must have taken the helmet to get help or...
先醒的人肯定拿了头盔去找人帮忙，或者……
Or leave us to die.
把我们丢下等死
Which I don't intend to do today. So...
我今天可不打算这么干，所以……
So, how much time do we have left?
那，我们还有多少时间？
I don't think I'm ready to go yet.
我觉得我还没准备好
I feel like shit.
我整个人都是焉的
Yeah, you and me both.
是啊，我们都一样
Cold, dehydrated, full of nasty drugs and low on blood sugar.
寒冷，脱水，药物副作用，再加上低血糖
It's a miracle you woke up at all.
你能醒过来真是个奇迹
Well, I have artificial heart and liver replacements.
我换了人工心脏和肝脏
Maybe it triggered some kind of fail-safe.
也许触发了某种应急机制吧
Maybe.
可能吧
Heart and liver, huh?
心脏和肝脏啊？
You got some wealthy parents, don't you?
你爹妈一定很有钱啊
Everyone on Earth has wealthy parents.
地球上的人谁爹妈不是有钱的
Yeah.
对啊
Bloody UN and their bloody birth control.
可恶的联合国，还有他们该死的避孕措施
I could have worked my tail off for ERG until I died
我为星际资源集团干到累死
and I would have never been able to afford the papers to have a kid.
可就是永远买不起生孩子的许可
Could have?
或许可以？
Yeah, damn right.
是啊，他妈的没错
I stole a freighter, kicked them goddamn Earthers out
我偷了一艘货船，把那些该死的地球人赶出去
and took my wife to a better place.
然后带我老婆去更好的地方
Sina's people took better care of us than Earth UN ever did.
西娜的人照顾我们，比联合国好太多了
Sina Stillwater?
西娜·斯蒂尔沃特？
So you're one of her outlaws.
所以你是她手下的那些亡命之徒吗？
We are not outlaws.
我们不是亡命之徒
We're pioneers.
我们是开拓者
We're building ourselves a new home away from Earth!
我们正在远离地球的地方建一个新家！
I don't think anyone would call Juno Station a home.
我可不认为有人会把朱诺空间站称作家
At least we can be who we want to be and have the families we want.
至少我们能做自己想做的事，拥有自己想要的家
I have three healthy kids now.
我现在有三个健康的孩子了
On Earth, that would have got me shipped to Vesta.
要是在地球上，我早就被送到维斯塔监狱了
But we are being shipped to Vesta right now.
但我们就是在被送到维斯塔监狱的路上啊
Yeah, right.
对啊
Okay, so I got caught.
好吧，我被抓了
Shit happens, all right?
背你妈的时
Still not regretting a damn thing.
脑袋掉了碗大个疤
How about you?
那你呢？
Well, I used to work for CommNet News
嗯，我以前是在CommNet新闻工作
until someone decided I was sticking my nose into matters I should have left alone.
直到有人说我多管闲事，去管了不该管的事
Government stuff?
政府那一套吗？
You bet.
你猜对了
Large-scale corruption.
大规模的贪腐
UN officials in bed with the Extraplanetary Resources Group.
联合国官员和星际资源集团勾结在一起
I broke into the CEO's CommNet account to get the proof.
我黑进了CEO的CommNet账户找证据
Unfortunately, a co-worker turned out to be on their payroll.
不幸的是，我的同事居然被收买了
Yeah.
好吧
He turned me in and that's how I got here.
他出卖了我，所以我才会到这儿来
Nice.
漂亮
So who's the outlaw now?
所以现在谁是法外狂徒了
Huh.
呵呵
What does that mean?
那是什么意思
It means someone's coming. Get behind me!
有人来了！赶紧躲到我后面！
What?
什么
You're alive?
你们还活着？
Yeah, no thanks to you.
是啊，我真是谢谢你
I'm sorry, I thought you were already...
对不起，我以为你们已经……
Dead.
死翘翘了
Yeah.
谢谢
So you're...
所以你是
Trent Binkin?
特伦特·宾金？
Yeah, that's me.
对，那是我
So Trent, what's cooking outside?
那特伦特，你在外面给我们做饭吗？
Made any new friends?
还是说在找朋友玩？
The crew.
机组成员
They're all dead.
他们都死了
Every single one of them.
每一个机组成员都死了
We're the only ones left alive.
这艘船上只要我们活着了
[Music: "Juno Rising" by Fox Amoore]
[Music: "Juno Rising" by Fox Amoore]
JUNO RISING
朱诺崛起
♪ And  what  all  do  we  have  left ♪
我们如今还余下些什么
♪ Comb  over  the  remnants ♪
拂过那些残存的痕迹
♪ The  way  I  used  to  turn ♪
一如我曾惯有的模样
♪ What  all were  we  looking  for ♪
我们当初都在寻觅些什么
♪ What  did  we  hope  to  find ♪
我们曾期盼寻得什么
♪ Besides  just  pain  and  dust ♪
难道只剩伤痛与尘埃散落
♪ No  sentence  yet  I’m  serving ♪
我尚未背负任何宣判
♪ It’s  much  too  hard  to  change  me ♪
要改变我，何其艰难
♪ As  I  see  the  Juno  rise ♪
当我看见朱诺升起
♪ Into  my  orbit ♪
进入我的轨道
♪ I  think  of  all  the  tired  eyes ♪
我念及所有疲惫的眼眸
♪ And  know, ♪
而后知晓
♪ I  already  chose  a  side ♪
我早已选定心之所向
♪ It  might  be  the  greatest  gift ♪
这或许是最珍贵的馈赠
♪ Providing  us  a  hiding  place ♪
为我们筑起一处栖身之境
♪ It  let  me  be  alone. ♪
让我得以独享这份寂静
♪ As  if  there  was  a  going  back ♪
仿佛真能回溯往昔那般
♪ Nothing  left  behind  can  pull  me  there ♪
但身后再无事物能将我牵绊
♪ What  was  has  been  erased ♪
过往早已被抹去
♪ Yet  we’re still fighting ♪
可我们仍在奋力抗争
♪ You  can’t  blame  me  for  trying ♪
你怎能怪我竭力一试
♪ I’m  gonna  live  while  dying ♪
我要在消逝中寻得生机
♪ Planets  still  reflect  the  light ♪
行星虽无法自放光芒
♪ though  they  don’t  produce  their own. ♪
却依旧折射着璀璨微光
♪ We  still  see  them  spinning  off ♪ ♪ and  always  moving. ♪
我们仍能看见它们旋转不息，永不停歇，奔赴远方
♪ As  I  see  the  Juno  rise ♪
当我看见朱诺升起
♪ Into  my  orbit ♪
进入我的轨道
♪ I  think  of  all  the  tired  eyes ♪
我念及所有疲惫的眼眸
♪ And  know, ♪
而后知晓
♪ I  already  chose  a  side ♪
我早已选定心之所向
♪ As  I  see  the  Juno  rise ♪
当我看见朱诺升起
♪ Into  my  orbit ♪
进入我的轨道
♪ I  think  of  all  the  tired  eyes ♪
我念及所有疲惫的眼眸
♪ And  know, ♪
而后知晓
♪ I  already  chose  a  side ♪
我早已选定心之所向
This is the bridge of the ship
这就是飞船的舰桥了
Happy now?
现在满意了吗？
Hell yeah!
真棒啊！
So let's see
让我们开始干活吧
Let me go and get over there
让让，我去那边一下
Let's see what we got here
让我看看我们都有什么
Sorry buddy
不好意思了，老弟
This ship is a SpaceX Rhino Mark 4
这艘船是SpaceX犀牛马克四型
Owner is the Extraplanetary Resources Group
归星际资源集团所有
Yeah, who else?
还能他妈是谁呢？
Could you fly it?
你能飞这个吗？
Totally
当然！
I mean, I don't have a type rating for this model
好吧，我没这种型号的驾照……
But who gives?
去他的吧
This is weird
这个挺奇怪的
What is weird?
什么奇怪？
The ship is on standby
飞船处于待命状态
Everything is properly shut down
所有系统已正常关闭
Main reactor's off, critical system are in backup power
主反应堆已关闭，备用电源在为重要系统供电
There is no sign of an emergency
看不出有什么紧急状况
Can we turn it back on?
我们能把它重新启动吗？
Hmm, let me see
让我试试
Nope, controls are locked
不行，控制系统锁死了
Computer, this is the captain speaking
电脑，我是船长
Unlock the controls
解锁控制系统
Complying
正在执行
Correction, unable to comply
更正：无法执行
System unlock requires a flight crew level override keycard
系统解锁需要飞行组级别的覆写密钥卡
Well, was worth a try I guess
好吧，至少我们试过了
Well, the flight crew is still here
得了，飞行组的还在这里
I'll see what they have
我去搜下身
Alright
好吧
How the hell did we lose pressure?
我们怎么他妈的会失压呢？
Each deck is divided into cells that automatically seal if there's a leak
每一层甲板都有自动密封的舱段，一旦有泄漏就会自动封闭
And even if someone circumvented all safety measures
就算有人绕过了所有安全措施
There's always the airlocks
也还有气闸
Two in the front and two in the back
前面两个，后面两个
Surviving decompression is part of ERG's basic training
撑过减压可是ERG的基础训练内容
So you're saying this massacre was intentional?
你的意思是，这场杀戮是有人故意干的？
I am not saying anything right now
我可什么都没说啊
Can we check the airlocks from here?
我们能在这里检查气闸吗？
Yeah, let's do that
行，让我试试
That's... what the?
这他妈的也太……
What is it?
这是什么？
The outer hatch is open
外部舱门处于开启状态
Huh, the second one too
唔，第二个外部舱门也是
Could this be how the ship was vented?
会不会就是这样导致飞船失压？
Unlikely, there's no way you can remotely open both sides
不太可能，不可能远程同时打开两边的舱门
Wow!
哇
Whoa, lookie there!
哇哦，看看这个
Survivors!
还有幸存者！
Airlock 4, let's go
4号气闸，我们走吧
Uh, not so fast
嗯，别急嘛
Why not?
为啥？
Because I say so
因为老子说的！
Ahhhhh!
啊啊啊啊！
Computer!
电脑！
Blacklist Trent Binkin from all access!
将特伦特·宾金列入黑名单，禁止一切访问！
Affirmative
收到
Shoot me, and you will die a very lonely death on this ship
有种就开枪，你会在这艘船上孤独地死去
Put the taser down, and we can talk
把电击枪放下，我们好好谈谈
Holy shit, you've got your wits together, girl
他妈的，你真机灵啊，姑娘！
You did all this, am I right?
这些都是你做的，对吗？
Shut up or else
闭嘴，不然我就……
Or else what?
不然你咋地
Without me, you're not going to get this ship anywhere
没老娘，你哪儿都去不了
And neither are you, because, well, I've got the keycard
而你自己也不行，因为嘛，密钥卡在我手上
I thought so. And what now?
我就知道，那现在怎么办
Maybe the card alone doesn't let me fly this ship
也许光有这张卡不能让我开走这艘船
But in all other aspects, it's still pretty much the backstage pass for this gig
但在其他方面，它基本就是这的后台通行证
Airlock security is still off
气闸的安全系统还没恢复
And all I have to do is flick this in front of a terminal
我只要在终端前轻轻一刷
And the survivors are gone
那他们就会死得连渣都没有
Do you want that?
你要试试吗
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa
等等，等等
Let's take it down a notch, shall we?
咱们先冷静点，行不？
No, you've got exactly five seconds to make me the captain
不行，你只有五秒钟把我升成船长
Five, four
五，四
Hold it!
停！
We are a bunch of convicted criminals on our way to the prison cap on Vesta
我们是一群被定罪的罪犯，正被押往维斯塔的监狱
We don't care about your business
我们不想掺和你的破事
We just want to get out of here alive
我们就想活着出去
Three, two
三，二
You can't be...
你逗我呢……
Alright, alright, for fuck's sake!
好好好，老娘不干了
Computer, transfer captain's privileges to Trant Binkin
电脑，把船长权限给特伦特·宾金！
Complying
执行中
Trant Binkin is now the captain
特伦特·宾金现在是船长了
Thank you, my dear
谢谢你，亲爱的
Computer, vent Airlock 4
电脑，清空4号气闸
Affirmative
收到
No!
不！
You son of a bitch, you murdered them
你这王八蛋，你杀了他们！
You fucking murdered...
你他妈杀了……
Pro tip, don't jump the guy with the gun
提醒你一句，七步以内枪快
MY HELMET! I ... CANT ... BREATHE ...
我的头盔！我……不能……呼吸……
Come over here
给老子爬过来
I am the only one who can save you now
你的狗命在老子手上
Now drop the goddamn stun gun
把他妈的电击枪放下！
Drop it!
给老子扔掉！
Come here
爬过来
Pro tip
给你个提示
Don't expect the taser to work very well through a space suit
隔着太空服，电击枪没啥作用
Lyra, are you alright?
莱拉，你还好吗？
Shit, that really, really hurt
操，这玩意儿真他妈疼！
But I think I'm okay
但我还行
Today's your lucky day, Trent.
算你狗日的走运，特伦特
Enough people have died on this ship already
今天船上已经死了够多人了
Captain Trent Binkin incapacitated
船长特伦特·宾金已失去行动能力
Transferring captain's rights to Lyra Senick according to emergency protocols
依照紧急程序，船长权限转给莱拉西尼克
So, here's the goddamn keycard
好了，这就是他妈的覆写密钥卡
Computer, complete authorization
电脑，完成授权
Please scan the flight crew override key
请扫描飞行组覆写密钥卡
Authorization confirmed
授权确认
Bridge controls unlocked
舰桥控制已解锁
Finally!
终于啊！
Let me go ahead...
接下来交给我吧……
Oh, hey!
喂！
First we're gonna gotta power this baby up
先得把这家伙启动起来
Reactor ready in 3, 2, 1
反应堆准备……3，2，1！
And now let's see if we have enough air to get at least this section repressurized
现在试试看，咱们有没有够的空气，把这一段重新加压
Let me see...
让我试试……
Ah
啊
And now let's get this thing to Juno Station before Earth notices we're missing
接下来得把这破船开到朱诺空间站
Time to strap in
系好安全带
Oh, wait a minute
喂，等一下
I'm the captain of this ship
老娘才是这船的船长
You're what?
你是啥？
-Can I help you? -Ahh, let me get this thing off first
需要帮忙吗？
Come on here, I'll show you how it's done. There we are!
过来，我给你示范一下，就这样！
Sheesh
唉哟
Computer, who's the captain?
电脑，谁是船长？
Captain on duty is Lyra Senick.
值班船长是莱拉·西尼克
Oh, I see!
嗷，我明白了
Well then...
那这样吧……
Tell me what to do, Miss Captain
船长女士，下命令吧
Huh!
嗯哼！
Mr. Sorin Jax?
索林·贾克斯先生
Energize!
开始传送！（《星际迷航》的梗）
This
啊这
This is not how any of this works, okay?
你指挥了个锤子！
Lighten up, it was a joke
放轻松嘛，我只是开个玩笑
Computer, grant full pilot's and navigation rights to Mr. Sorin Jax!
电脑，授予索林·贾克斯先生完整的驾驶与导航权限！
Affirmative
收到
Thank you
感谢
Now, fasten your seatbelts, everyone!
各位，系好安全带！
This is going to be a high G burn
接下来推背感会很强
Standby for acceleration in 5, 4, 3, 2, 1
加速准备，5，4，3，2，1
Yes!
好耶！
Bureau of Investigation, Detective Tony White
调查局，侦探托尼·怀特
What can I do for you?
我能为你做什么？
I am trying to reach Deputy Chief Erickson
我想联系副局长埃里克森
Oh, I'm sorry, sir, but Mr. Erickson is currently not available
抱歉，先生，埃里克森目前不在
But if you let me know the nature of your inquiry, I'll be more than happy to...
不过，如果您向我报告，我很乐意……
Then patch me through to Chief.
那就把我接到局长那去
Oh, I'm afraid Chief Lewis is not taking calls at this time.
恐怕路易斯局长现在接不了电话
Look, I have a very sensitive matter to report.
听着，我有件非常敏感的事情要汇报
I need to talk to someone in charge!
必须找负责人！
Oh, I am 100% in charge for criminal reports
哦，我百分百负责刑事案件报告
And I promise your matter will be in safe hands with me, sir!
先生，我保证您的事交给我准没问题！
Are you new here? Do you even know who I am?
你是新来的吧？你知道我是谁吗？
It's my first day here, yes
是的，今天是我第一天在这上班
And you are Theodore Copeland
我知道您是西奥多·科普兰
Director of Fleet Operations of the Extraplanetary Resources Group
星际资源集团舰队运营总监
Damn right!
这他妈不就对了
And you're now going to tell me how to reach either Lewis or Erickson
现在你得告诉我怎么联系到路易斯或埃里克森
Or is this also going to be your last day?
还是说这也是你最后一天上班？
Oh, I wish I could, but I can't
我知道你很急，但你先别急
You see, they have both been suspended from duty
你看，他们两人都已被停职
What? This is the first time I've heard of it
什么？我第一次听说这事
Why wasn't I informed?
为什么没人通知我？
Excuse me, sir, but are you a member of this agency?
抱歉，先生，您是本机构成员吗？
I've known Lewis and Erickson for longer than you can read or write
我认识他俩时，你还在穿尿布
They're still of the old guard
他们是老干部了
They know how to get things done
他们知道怎么完成任务
And who to call when something important happens!
知道关键时刻该联系谁！
Not like you, fresh out of college
不像你，刚出大学
But too afraid to wipe your own ass without filing a request first
又他妈怕自己动手擦屁股，非得先提申请
Well, there's no official statement about the reason of their suspension
官方没有公布他们停职原因
But if I had to guess
但我猜
It was probably because it wasn't just their own asses they've been wiping
估计他们擦的可不止是自个儿的屁股
And by the way, this call is being recorded
顺便说一句，这通电话正在录音
So if you enjoy talking yourself into trouble
所以如果你喜欢给自己找麻烦
By all means, just keep going!
就继续说下去吧
All right.
好吧
One of our ships is missing.
我们的一艘船失踪了
Reg number 85473362
注册号85473362
Finally, we're getting somewhere!
终于开始说正事了！
Hang on...
等下……
A Mark IV Rhino named Darwin
一艘名叫达尔文的犀牛马克四型
Departed July 25th from Bogota, Colombia
从7月25日哥伦比亚波哥大出发
Destination Vesta Station
目的地维斯塔站
Left controlled space to sector 4385
离开管制区进入4385区
No voluntary tracking
未主动开启追踪
Let me send you the flight data
我发给你飞行数据
It'll show you exactly when we lost contact.
你可以看到我们失去联系的准确时间
Okay, I see
明白了
And what makes you think the loss is the result of a criminal offense?
那么你为什么认为这是犯罪行为？
Because it happened in the middle of pioneer territory!
因为发生在开拓者领地啊！
Have you ruled out any technical failure?
你排除技术故障了吗？
We're talking about the kidnapping of 25 crew members
我们在说25名船员被绑架
Millions worth of cargo for Vesta and Ceres
价值百万的货物
And three federal prisoners.
还有三名联邦囚犯……
Four.
不，是四名
What?
什么？
The manifest lists four prisoners in cryo
申报单上有四名囚犯
Whatever!
随你的便！
If they had prisoners on board, why didn't you have an escort?
既然押送囚犯，为什么不派护航？
Because the idiots in your department didn't provide one!
因为你们部门的白痴没提供！
There was a military vessel
原本有军舰
Scheduled to join your freighter the next day
第二天要会合你的货船
Yes, a whole day!
整整一天！
Do you even know what that costs?
你知道这要花多少钱吗？
Sir, that transport was a violation of federal regulations
先生，这次运输违反联邦规定
And the prisoner transport also means I have to get the Department of Justice involved.
押送囚犯也意味着我必须通知司法部
Listen, you little bean-counter
听着，你这抠细账的
Are you going to help me or not?
帮我还是不帮？
Oh, I am trying, but...
我在努力，但……
You know what? Forget I called you.
算了，别说我给你们打过电话
I'm withdrawing my report.
我撤回报告
I'm going to call the military instead.
打给军方算了
Time to learn how to wipe your own ass, Mr. Copeland.
科普兰先生，是时候学会自己擦屁股了
What a moron.
烂泥扶不上墙
Bureau of Investigation, Detective Tony White.
调查局，侦探托尼·怀特
What can I do for you?
我能为你做什么？
Welcome to Juno Station.
欢迎来到朱诺空间站
Please identify yourself and state the intention of your visit.
请说明身份，并说明来访目的
Didn't you get the documents I emailed you an hour ago?
你没收到我一个小时前发的邮件吗？
Well, yes.
额，好吧
Yes, we did.
我们确实收到了
But you arrived here on a stolen freighter with a full cargo hold
但你是开着偷来的货船来的，船舱里满载货物
And no proof of identification whatsoever
而且一点身份证明都没有
The only reason we let you even dock here
我们之所以允许你停靠
was that our scans only showed three men and lots of cargo on board.
是扫描显示船上只有三个人，还有一堆货物
Look, I explained everything in my email.
听着，我已经在邮件里解释了一切！
My name is Sorin Jax, I'm a pioneer.
我叫索林·贾科斯，是一位开拓者
I have family in Habitat Level 31, Third Quadrant.
我家人在31号居住区，第三区
Look it up if you don't believe me!
不信的话就去查一查！
There's only one Sorin Jax on our records
我们的记录里只有一个索林·贾克斯
And he's been missing for more than a year.
而且他已经失踪一年多了
Yeah, and now I'm back!
对，老子这不是回来了吗！
I don't care about your life story!
我不在乎你的小故事
Everyone who comes through these doors has one.
每个进这门的都有一堆这种故事
And you know why this station still exists?
你知道为什么这个空间站一直存在吗？
Because I don't believe everything I hear.
因为老子一点都不信你的狗屁
If you don't have a proper ID, you have two options
如果你没有身份证的话，你有两个选择
You can sign Form A, that's for trade.
你可以签A表格，适用于贸易
Or Form B, that's if you want to seek political asylum
或者B表格，如果你想申请政治庇护的话
And until either of these is approved
在生效之前
You are going to stay on your ship.
你都得在你的船上乖乖待着
The lease for your dock expires in 24 hours
你的船位24小时后到期
Power is free, enjoy your stay.
电力免费，尽情享用吧
Will you cut the crap and let me in?
少废话，让我进去！
I used to live here, goddammit!
我以前住在这儿，你妈的！
Damn, this place is falling apart.
靠，这地方都快散架了
Alright, I want to trade.
行吧，我是来搞贸易的
No problem!
没问题！
All I need from you is Form A, your contract, and a detailed packing list
我只需要你提供A表格，合同，以及详细的装箱清单
What if I don't have a contract?
如果我没有合同呢？
There's a section for trade offers on our network.
我们的网络上有一个贸易报价专区
How about you?
要不这样呢？
Personally? I happen to have a full container of wallpaper paste.
恰好我有整整一箱墙纸胶
Oops, and the price just went up!
哎哟，我得涨点价了！
Better act quickly!
快点吧！
Are you trying to bribe me?
你这是想贿赂我吗？
Maybe we should try political asylum instead
也需要我们该申请政治庇护
We are refugees after all.
我们这样反正算难民
What? You really want to stay on this rust bucket?
什么？你真想住这个破铁桶里？
What? This is my home!
那咋了？这里是我的家！
Excuse me sir, how long does an application usually take?
请问一下，先生，申请一般要多久？
Not very long, a month maybe, or two
不太长，一般需要一个月，或者两个月
Are you kidding me?
你特么在逗我？
Back when I moved in, it didn't take longer than a day!
我以前搬进来的时候，一天都不到就办完了！
The safety of our community is our highest priority.
保障社区安全是我们的首要任务
How cool is that?
我发现个好东西
Sorin, look
索林，来看这个
What?
什么？
Did you know we had twelve and a half tons of coffee beans on board?
你知道吗？我们船上居然有十二吨半的咖啡豆！
Oh
哇哦
There, right next to the three containers full of chocolate pudding.
就在那儿，三个集装箱的巧克力布丁旁边
Hold it right there, what did you just say?
等一下，你刚才说了啥？
Coffee beans and chocolate pudding!
咖啡豆和巧克力布丁！
Hang on, I've got to make a call.
稍等！我得打个电话！
That was brilliant!
干得漂亮！
I think you found their weak spot.
我觉得你抓到了他们的软肋了
Of course!
当然！
Please wait, someone is on their way to meet with you.
请稍等！有人来这里见你们了
Prepare to have your load inspected.
请准备货物检查
That's what she said!
她也是这么说的！（《办公室》的梗）
Don't ruin it
别露馅了！
What?
咋了？
Sorin! You? Here?
索林！你回来啦？
I thought they had caught you and sent you to Vesta!
我以为他们把你抓起来扭送到维斯塔了！
Yeah, can't believe it myself!
对啊，我自己也没想到！
Oh god, it's so good to see you!
老天爷啊，见到你真高兴！
Yeah, you too!
我也一样
Wait, you know each other?
等等，你们互相认识？
You and Sina Stillwater, Chief Commander of the Pioneers?
你和西娜·斯蒂尔沃特，开拓者首席指挥官？
Yeah, why?
对啊，咋了？
This could have been so much easier!
那我们的事情就简单了！
Calm down, they wouldn't have patched me through to her anyways.
冷静点，他们反正不会让她给我们提供便利
That's a nice new ship you have there!
吊飞船靓得一比啊
Actually, it's my ship.
实际上，那是我的船
Oh yeah, right, and I am just the lowly pilot.
哦对了，我只是个卑微的飞行员
And who the hell is she?
你几把谁啊？
I am Lyra Senick, refugee and freelance journalist
我是莱拉·西尼克，难民兼自由记者
Well, pleased to make your acquaintance, Mrs. Freelance Refugee!
很高兴认识你，自由难民小姐！
If you want any of the coffee, you'd better take me seriously!
想喝咖啡的话，最好把我当回事儿！
I like the way you think.
英雄所见略同啊
Don't worry, here on Juno we take everyone seriously.
别担心，在朱诺这儿，我们重视每个人
Especially those who have lost their faith in Earth like you.
尤其是像你一样，对地球失望了的人
Welcome to your new life, Lyra!
欢迎你，莱拉，开始你的新生活吧！
What if I don't want a new life?
我要是不想要新生活呢？
Once you've experienced what true freedom is like, you will never want to go back
一旦体验过真正的自由，你就不想回去了
I promise you that!
我跟你打包票！
Officer, could you please get the paperwork done for these two people?
请帮这两位办理相关手续好吗？
Consider them cleared for immigration.
他们已通过移民审查
But... But...
但是……但是……
Oh, and if you could get it done in the next five minutes, that would be really great.
如果你能在接下来的五分钟内办好，那就太好了
You have my permission to keep your mouth shut, thank you.
我允许你把狗嘴闭上，谢谢
Now come on, I bet you have one hell of a story to tell, and I want to hear all of it!
搞快搞快！我猜你肯定有段好耍的故事，赶紧跟我摆完！
Uh, Sina, there's one more little thing...
额，西娜，还有一件小事……
Yes?
咋了？
We are actually three.
实际上我们有三个人
Oh, I see.
哦，我知道了
Officer, we need another copy, please.
劳驾，再多弄一份
No, no, no, I don't think you want that.
不不不，我觉得你不会喜欢的
He is our prisoner, he tried to kill us.
我们抓住他了，刚才还试图杀我们
Seriously?
搞毛线哦？
And why didn't you just kick him out the airlock?
你们为啥不直接把那孙子踢到气闸外面呢？
Well...
呃……
Everyone on this ship died because of him!
船上所有人都是他害死的！
Yeah, and what am I supposed to do with him?
行，那我该怎么收拾他？
Put him in jail?
把他关进监狱？
And who's gonna pay for this?
谁来付钱呢？
You?
你？
He managed to break out of cryo and single-handedly kill every person on board
他竟然能从冷冻舱里逃出来，一个人干掉了整船的人
and would have hijacked this freighter for himself if it hadn't been for us.
要不是我们，他早就把这艘货船给劫走了
It's all way too sophisticated for a simple robbery.
这绝对不是单纯的抢劫，手段太专业了
Maybe you can get some info out of him!
也许你能从他嘴里撬出点东西！
That sounds like someone we might have a use for.
这人嘛，说不定还能被我们利用一下
We can't trust him!
我们不能全信他！
Ah, leave it to me, I'm a professional.
嗨，放心交给我吧，老娘是专业的！
Yeah, she's right, she knows what she's doing. I'll be right back.
对，她没错，她懂行，我去去就回
I have a bad feeling about this.
我心里头有点发毛
So there he is.
我把他带来了
He says his name is Trent.
他说他的名字叫特伦特
Trent Binkin, probably in alias.
特伦特·宾金，大概是个假身份
Well, get rid of the tape, I want to talk to him.
好，把那胶布给我撕了，我得问问他
Alright
行
Be careful though, he will tell you everything you want to hear!
你要留个心眼，他净捡你想听的讲！
The ship's a bomb, we're all going to die!
这艘船有个炸弹，我们全都要死了！
Oh well, that's definitely not what I wanted to hear
靠，这消息我可一点都不想听
Red alert, red alert!
红色警报，红色警报！
Evacuate sections A to C immediately!
A到C区人员立即撤离！
This is not a drill, I repeat, this is not a drill!
这不是演习，重复一次，这不是演习！
Red alert!
红色警报！
Stop! Stop, stop, stop!
停！停，停，停！
Places everyone, starting over.
各就各位，重新来一遍！
Listen, listen, it's not too late yet.
听着，听着！现在还不太晚！
The time is running, but if you let me free, I can stop it!
炸弹还在倒计时！但如果你把我放开，我就能停下倒计时！
So, you say there's a bomb on this ship?
所以，你是说那艘船上有个炸弹
The biggest one you've ever seen!
比你这辈子见过的都大！
But be more specific!
说具体点！
Matter, antimatter
物质，反物质
doesn't matter!
去他的！
It's like a SD-Z/4, similar containment, but twice the capacity
类似SD-Z/4，结构类似，但是容量翻了一倍
But that's insane, who builds something like that?
这也太扯了！谁会整个这种东西出来？
Someone who wants the entire system to see their fireworks.
就是那种想让全星系都看他放烟花的人
Earth, of course.
肯定是地球啦
Yeah, but who on Earth?
废话，地球上的哪个人？
If I told you, I'd be a dead rat!
如果我说了，我会死得梆硬！
Why do they want to destroy us?
他们为什么要摧毁我们！
I have no idea!
我不知道！
What about the crew of the freighter?
那货船上的船员呢？
Faking an emergency and sending a mayday was the easiest way to get the bomb to Juno.
假装紧急情况，发求救信号，就能把炸弹运到朱诺
And as you can see, it worked like a charm!
你看吧，效果好得不得了！
You really should work on your security!
你们安保措施真是拉跨！
You better tell me where that bomb is, or
你最好坦白炸弹在哪里，不然……
Or what?
不然怎么？
OR...
那么……
Listen to me
听说我
Here's what I have to offer.
这是我能开出的条件
If you tamper with the containment or try to remove it from the station, it will explode.
要是你动了这个集装箱，或者想把它搬出空间站，它就会爆炸
The timer was activated the moment the ship entered the dock
计时器在飞船进港的那一刻就已经启动了
This was supposed to give me time to leave before everyone blows up!
本来这是为了让我在爆炸前逃走！
The mechanism can only be deactivated by the same person who activated it
这个装置只有启动它的人才能解除
Me!
老子！
And why are you telling us all this?
那你为什么要告诉我们这些？
Because I might be a greedy and heartless bastard
虽然我可能是个没心没肺的王八蛋
but I'd rather not turn into plasma!
但我也不想变成一团等离子体
Easy, isn't it?
很简单的道理
You are a miserable piece of shit.
你个讨人嫌的瘟丧
But at least you are a piece of shit that makes sense.
但你脑壳还没遭门夹
I can work with that.
我理解了
Fine, let me walk free and we will all live to see another day.
那就把我放开，这样我们都能活下去
Under one condition!
只有一个条件！
The bomb stays with me.
把炸弹留在我这里
Deal?
同意吗？
Deal!
同意！
So, this is the bomb container?
所以，这就是装着炸弹的集装箱？
Yes.
对头
Okay.
行吧
Wait, are you crazy?
等下，你脑子被门夹了吗？
One wrong move, and we're gonna blow to bits!
一不小心，我们所有人都会死得连渣都没有！
Let me do this!
让我来！
How do we know it's not a trap?
这会不会是在坑我们啊？
Listen, Brainiac, in case you haven't noticed, we're all sitting in the same boat.
听着，带聪明！咱们都在一条船上
I don't want to die, just as you don't want to die.
我还没活够，你应该也没活够吧
He's right, let the man do his job.
他说的对，让他干活吧
I hope he knows what he's doing.
我希望他知道自己在干啥
Here we go...
就是这里了……
Step one, disarm the watchdog.
第一步，解除看门狗
What was that?
刚才那是什么？
You mean, apart from the moment you shat your pants?
你是说，你刚才尿裤子的时候吗？
I'll show you who...
我要给你点颜色……
Will you shut up?
能不能把你狗嘴闭上！
Alright, step two, reset the trigger program...
好，第二步，重置触发程序……
General Stillwater, with all due respect, but you just can't stand here and do nothing!
斯蒂尔沃特将军，恕我直言，您不能在那里干瞪眼！
I said shut up!
把你狗嘴闭上！
Thank you.
谢了
Now, step three, deactivate the bomb...
接下来，第三步，解除炸弹……
Alright, that's it. She's all yours!
好了，完成了，她现在归你了！
Thank you!
谢谢！
You're welcome.
不客气
Oh, and I hereby apply for political asylum at Juno Station.
我现在正式申请在朱诺空间站的政治庇护
Before I grant you asylum, I have to know who sent you.
批准之前，我得先知道到底是谁派你来的
Hey, that wasn't part of our deal!
喂，这不在我们的交易里啊！
The deal just changed.
交易现在已经改了
Look, if I told you, you might as well just shoot me!
如果我说了，你可能会让我吃子弹！
Alright, if that's what you want.
行，我看你厕所里灯笼——找死！
What?
什么？
Fucking idiot.
像你这种要求我这辈子都没听过！
And that's how I learned to stop worrying and love the bomb!
于是我明白了：别怕炸弹，学会爱它！
Oh, what an idiot indeed!
哟，还真是个瓜娃子！
What the hell did he... What the hell did he expect?
他以为……他在期待些什么啊！
To the bomb!
敬炸弹！
Whatever...
去他的吧……
Yes!
好耶！
Hell yeah
痛快啊
What's up with you, Lyra?
莱拉，你怎么了？
Not in the mood for a party?
没心情好好玩玩吗？
Yeah, I don't know...
是啊，我不明白……
I know he was a bad guy, but it still feels wrong to me.
我清楚他不是啥好货，但心里总觉得过意不去
Oh, seriously?
锤子哦
That guy tried to murder us!
那孙子想杀了我们呢！
And he even tried to kill you twice!
而且是想杀你们两次！
So you're incredibly lucky that you're still alive!
你能活下来真的很幸运！
Sorry for having a conscience.
抱歉，我还有点良心
For that guy, our deal was off the moment that bomb stopped ticking.
那家伙？炸弹一停，我们的交易就算作废了
Simple game theory.
简单的博弈论
Yeah, and she'd also give you a witty quote from The Art of War
对，她还会整点《孙子兵法》来逗你
When she's too drunk to remember!
等她醉得连自己都记不得的时候！
Oh, shut up and drink!
闭嘴快点喝吧！
Ah, yeah.
啊，我知道了
Your tactical training.
你的战术训练
I get it.
我明白了
It's all professional.
非常专业
Killing people while delivering funny one-liners.
一边杀人，还一边讲些搞笑的话
Which school did you go to again?
你和哪个师傅学的啊？
Schwarzenegger University?
施瓦辛格吗？
Jeez, lighten up!
妈耶，敞亮点吧！
We're not on Earth anymore!
我们又不在地球上！
This is how you survive out here!
这就是这里的生存法则！
Yeah, and it's also why I'd rather go back home than stay here.
没错，所以我宁可回家，也不想待在这里
But that's not an option right now, so you'd better get used to it!
反正你现在也回不去，既来之则安之！
Yeah, and what the hell
对啊，我才注意到
Don't you ever get drunk?
你是千杯不醉吗？
I mean, you had twice as much boozamahol as Sorin
你喝的烈酒可是索林的两倍！
And he's got some training!
他还被练过呢！
Yep!
没错！
I'm afraid not.
那倒不是
Artificial liver.
人工肝脏
Breaks it right down the moment it hits my bloodstream
酒精一进入血液就被分解了
And that means no buzz for me!
所以酒精不会进脑子
I am... I am so, so sorry!
我……我真的很抱歉！
I'm sure she knows some weird-ass engineer in the belt who can make that adjustable...
她认识某个小行星带的古怪工程师，能帮你微调下……
Alright, I think it's time to call it a night.
好啦，我觉得今晚就到这儿吧
Ah, come on, come on, come on, please stay, come on.
拜托，拜托，别走，拜托
I'll turn the belter humor down a notch for you, okay?
我会把小行星带那套幽默收敛一点，好吗？
Yeah!
对啊！
Today is the first day of your new life after all!
今天反正是你新生的第一天！
Yes it is, and you know what? It's damn scary.
是啊，而且你知道吗？简直吓死人了
I've never been farther away from Earth than the moon.
我还从没到过比月球更远的地方
And I'm homesick! like crazy!
我现在想家得不得了！
Well, everyone here had the price to pay to stay alive, you know.
这里每个人为了活下去都付出过代价
I've never been much fun at parties
我向来不怎么会玩派对
Sorry I can't just wash away my worries with booze like you.
抱歉，没法像你一样，靠喝酒就能把烦心事都冲掉
Your iron heart saved my life.
你的钢铁心脏救了我
Maybe one day your iron liver will too.
也许有一天你的钢铁肝脏也会
And who knows what other hidden superpowers you have?
说不定你还有别的隐藏技能呢？
Apart from being the designated driver? Not many.
除了当代驾？没了
Well, at least you can sell my parts for scraps when I die.
至少在我死后，你能把我拆了卖钱
See? That's the spirit!
看看！要的就是这种精神！
You two act like you're high school buddies.
你俩就像高中同学一样
Almost. We've known each other for a long time.
差不多，我们认识很久了
Yeah.
对啊
Sorin was one of the very first pioneers.
索林是最早的一批开拓者
Yep!
正是！
Back then we were still the tightly knit band of brothers and sisters!
当年我们就像亲姐弟一样
Huh! Today I can barely keep track of who's working at my own office.
哼！现在嘛，我连办公室的人都认不全
Sina Stillwater.
西娜·斯蒂尔沃特
Adopted daughter of Meredith Stillwater, CEO of Stillwater Dynamics
梅雷迪思·斯蒂尔沃特（斯蒂尔沃特动力公司CEO）
and John Stillwater, UN military officer.
和约翰·斯蒂尔沃特（联合国军官）收养的女儿
Military college graduate, best in her class.
军校毕业，班上成绩最优
Spotless military career.
军事生涯无可挑剔
Leading off-world police operations with the rank of a master sergeant.
现担任星际警务行动负责人，军衔为上士
Yep, that's my Wikipedia article.
对，搜狗上是这么写的
What's your point?
觉得咋样？
One day you defected to the dark side, gave up everything you lived for
有一天，你投向了黑暗，放弃了曾经为之而活的一切
and decided to fight the system you once swore by.
决定反抗那个你曾誓死效忠的系统
But why?
但为什么？
What turned Sina Stillwater the patriot into Sina Stillwater the revolutionary?
究竟是什么，让爱国者西娜变成了革命者西娜？
The power of love!
当然是爱情的力量！
Shut up Sina, you're drunk!
闭嘴吧，西娜！你喝麻了！
No, I'm serious!
不，我认真的！
The man of my dreams
我梦中的男人
And he opened my eyes to the truth!
他让我看到了真相！
Ah Sina, quit the bullshit!
得了吧，西娜！
Alright, story time!
好了，故事时间！
Privacy please!
给我们点私人空间！
Listen up, cause I'm going to tell you something
听好了，现在我要说一些
that even good old Sorin here may not know about me!
连老油条索林都不知道的故事
Uh oh...
哦吼……
They were setting up that new mining operation
他们在筹建新的矿业项目时
Davi something, in the asteroid belt.
叫什么戴维什么的吧，在小行星带
It was boring as hell, so I decided to have a little fun.
无聊得爆，所以我决定找点乐子
I had a crush on one of the workers in the setup crew
我暗恋上筹建队伍里的一名工人
What?
什么？
And so I asked him out on a date.
所以我把他勾引出来约会
We ended up spending a lot of time together
后来我们大部分时间都腻歪在一起
And he taught me how different the world looked from a miner's perspective.
他让我明白了，从矿工的视角看世界，有多么不一样
I keep getting new assignments all over the system
我在星系里不停被调动
But we wanted to stay together
但我们想一直在一起
So I had to choose between him and the military.
所以我得在他和军队里做个选择
So it was more like the power of hormones, right?
你是荷尔蒙上脑了对吧？
No!
当然不是！
I loved him!
我是真爱他！
And his simple way of life.
还有他的单纯生活
Honest work.
诚实工作
No politics.
不谈政治
The whole career madness had worn me out.
这工作折腾得我够呛
All I wanted was my own home and kids.
我只想要一个家和孩子
A family like in the old days!
传统的家庭
But the powers that be just couldn't tolerate it.
可上面的人根本无法容忍
My family had my future carefully laid out for me.
我的家人为我规划好了未来
And they hated my chains of plans.
他们恨我打破这些规划
I was denied permission to have my own child
我甚至被拒绝了拥有自己孩子
And then one day, Albio disappeared.
然后有一天，阿尔比奥消失了
Albio?
阿尔比奥？
Albio Sengo.
阿尔比奥·森戈
My love.
我的爱人
The day they picked me up to have my pregnancy terminated
他们带我去流产的那一天
Was the last time I saw him.
是我最后一次见到他
His workplace deserted.
他的工作地点空无一人
His name removed from the records.
他的名字从记录里被抹去了
His CommNet account
他的CommNet账号注销了
They did not even give him a chance to leave me a message.
他们甚至没给他机会留言
That's when I knew I could never be part of that system again.
那时候我就明白，我成为不了那个系统里的一员
I had been fighting for the wrong side all my life
我一辈子都在错误的一边战斗
But if you're officially the other side now
但你现在完全是敌人了
Why didn't Earth just try to attack you?
为什么地球不攻击你呢？
I don't know.
我不知道啊
If I had to guess, it's because there's no profit in blowing me up.
我猜，炸了我这里也没好处
Until now, apparently.
但是现在不是了
That would almost be a compliment.
难得他们注意到我
And it will be my pleasure to send this little gift back to Earth.
我很乐意把这个小礼物送回地球！
Oh, can we please talk about this once again?
拜托，我们能不能等清醒的时候再聊这个？
And this is really not a good time to make decisions of that magnitude.
现在根本不是做这么大决定的时候
That's the designated driver talking right there!
看，这就是代驾说的话
I have friends and family on Earth
我的朋友和家人都是在地球上
It's my home!
那是我的家
Lyra is right, you know.
莱拉是对的
Let's postpone the launch until we all can think straight again.
先别计划了，等大家都能清醒思考再说
Thank you!
谢谢
Please excuse her.
请原谅她
The power sometimes gets to her head when she's drunk.
她一喝多就瞎闹腾
Let's talk about something else!
我们来聊点别的吧
Is there anything I can do to make you feel better?
我能做些什么，让你舒服一点吗？
Some sugar might help.
可能来点甜点
That reminds me, we still have to do some business!
这倒提醒我了，我们还有件事没做
Here's a quote for the containers BZ21 rows 3 to 6
这是BZ21集装箱第3到6排的报价单
Do we have a deal?
我们要来点吗！
Hell yeah we do!
当然，整起！
Wait a minute, that's my...
等下，那个是我的……
Relax, you're both getting 50-50, alright?
放心，你们俩平分，行吗？
Deactivate privacy.
取消私人空间！
Sorin, what's in BZ21 rows 3 to 6?
索林，BZ21第三排到第六排有什么
Chocolate pudding for everyone!
巧克力布丁！人人有份！
Access, schmackcess. Let's try something else.
权限算个屁，换个方法试试
Maybe...
可能……
Damn, this is going to take ages without proper CommNet access!
靠，没有CommNet权限，慢死了！
Why now?
为啥现在啊！
Uh, hey Lyra!
莱拉你在吗！
Sorry...
不好意思……
What is it?
有屁快放！
We've got a problem.
这里有个小麻烦
There is this guy who wants to buy this...
有人想要买……
What was it called again?
这玩意儿叫啥来着……
A reverse-ratcheting routing planer.
逆向棘轮型路径规划器（这是个《星际迷航》的梗）
Uh yeah, what he said.
对，就是他说的这个
Do you know where it is?
你知道这个在哪里吗？
Yeah, let me check.
好，我查一下
Ah yes, it's in the container, all the way in the back, under the air filter.
就在那集装箱里，最里面，空气过滤器下面
Ah, gotcha!
好，收到！
Oh, and Sorin?
对了，索林？
Yes?
怎么？
Would you mind lending me your CommNet ID?
我能借一下你的 CommNet ID吗？
I'm trying to do some research, and mine got blocked a while ago.
我想做点调查，但我的账号被封了了
You are not going to do something illegal with it, are you?
你不会用这个做违法的事情吧？
Not more illegal than stealing an ERG freighter?
比偷了ERG运输船还非法？
Just don't burn it, okay?
别让我也被封了，好吗？
We can be glad we're getting CommNet out here at all.
能在这儿用上CommNet，就已经很幸运了
Uuh, here's the key, sending now.
呃，这是我的密钥，正在传输……
Thanks!
感谢！
Computer, remind me to look up what a reverse-ratcheting routing planer is.
电脑，记得提醒我去查一下逆向棘轮型路径规划器是什么
Affirmative, reminder has been added to calendar.
收到，已添加到日历
Now we're talking!
现在开始网上冲浪！
And this station is still an active relay!
这个地方居然都能连上网
Those corporate idiots!
好吃懒做的废物！
That's what you get for not giving a shit about security.
这就是不在乎安全的下场！
And here we go...
终于查到了……
What is it this time?
现在又咋了？
Um, captain, we got a problem again. That thing...
呃，船长，我们又遇到个问题，那个啥……
Reverse-ratcheting routing...
逆向棘轮型路径……
Yes, I know!
行，我知道！
Well, that thing weighs like a ton and he didn't bring a pallet jack.
哎呀，那玩意儿得有一吨重，他居然没带叉车
Well, tough luck. If he can't move it, I've got five...
唉，运气不好啊，他搬不动的话，我这里还有五……
No, six other interested parties for that item.
不，六个其他买家盯着这东西呢
Righty-O.
好嘞
Selling at this station is worse than clearing out your attic on Craigslist.
清理货舱比在闲鱼卖二手还恼火
Now for those credentials...
现在我来试试密码……
Access granted.
允许访问
What? On the first try?
什么？一次就成功？
No way, don't they ever swap out their keys?
开玩笑吧，他们不换密码吗？
Okay, download. Everything!
好，下载，全部！
Oh, no, no, no, no, no, no, don't trace me back, please...
不不不，不要反向追踪！不要啊……
Oh, sorry, what the fuck?
请问，你还有什么屁事！
Sorry, Lyra, I really have...
不好意思，莱拉，我不得不……
I paid for it!
我付了钱的！
Why won't you give it to me?
你为啥不给我？
I'm trying to find a solution here, okay?
我在想办法，好吗
Listen, do you know how many years I've been waiting
听者，你知道我等了多少年……
to get my hands on a reverse-ratcheting routing planer?
才买到这个逆向棘轮型路径规划器
I'm not going to let myself be scammed by some earthen bitch like you!
我才不会让自己被你这个地球来的贱人骗了！
Get the fuck out of my face! Aaaahh!
给老子爬开！
Lyra, could you turn off the Grav-Gen for a minute?
莱拉，你可以把重力发生器关掉一分钟吗？
Then we can push the bloody box out of the pad and...
我们就能把这玩意儿弄出来，然后……
And then have security handle this guy, okay?
让保安来收拾这个家伙，好吗？
The what?
啥玩意儿？
Artificial gravity, turn it off
人工重力，关掉它
Ship console, maintenance settings, environment, impulse, Grav-Gen.
飞船控制台，维护模式，环境，推进，重力发生器
Okay...
好的……
Just uncheck the box on the left.
把左边的框点一下
Okay, got it!
好了！
Oh, and Sorin?
对了，索林？
Yes?
怎么了？
You don't incidentally have another commit ID?
你还有别的ID吗？
What?
什么？
Great, just great
真是太棒了
Warning, safety hazard.
警告，安全风险
Please hold on to the nearest handrail.
请抓紧最近的扶手
GravGen shutting down
重力发生器关闭中
In 3, 2, 1
3, 2, 1
I'm not falling...
我没掉下去……
Oh shit, I forgot my coffee...
完了，我忘了我的咖啡了……
Oh, hey, wait, stay here!
等等，快给我回来！
I hate it when this happens!
我真是烦死这个了！
Hurry up, Sorin!
快点，索林！
Oh, please tell me you're done!
请告诉我你做完了！
Almost there!
快了！
Just a few seconds...
还有几秒……
And he's outside!
我拿出来了
Aaaaaa! My tail! Get it off! Get it off!
啊啊！我的尾巴！快拿走！快拿走！
That's it, I'm coming upstairs.
完工，我现在上来
Over and out.
通话结束，下线
Warning, safety hazard.
警告，安全风险
Please hold on to the nearest handrail.
请抓紧最近的扶手
Grav-Gen starting up
重力生成器启动中
In 3, 2, 1
3, 2, 1
Computer, cleanup spillage in captain's room.
电脑，把船长室地上的东西收拾干净
Complying...
正在执行
Correction, unable to comply.
更正，无法执行
No survey staff available.
无服务人员在岗
No cleaner bots? Where's the ship from?
扫地机器人也没有吗？这船哪里来的？
The Middle Ages?
中世纪吗？
Computer, lights on.
电脑，开灯！
Oh no, what a mess!
我去，一团糟啊！
At least the download finished before they could shut me down.
至少在我被踢掉之前，下载完成了
And bingo, here's our missing link!
好耶，这就是我要找的链接……
Oh, oh, hey
嗷，你好啊
I'm so sick and tired of this!
我真是受够这些了！
Caution!
小心
Thank God it's Fridayyyyyyyy
感谢老天爷，今天是周五……
Wet floor.
地滑
I hate gravity.
我讨厌重力
And I hate the absence of gravity.
我讨厌没有重力
I nearly threw up my lunch!
我差点把午饭都吐出来了！
Ugh
呃
Have you ever thrown up out of the window of a moving car?
你曾经从开着的车上，往车窗外呕吐过吗？
In Zero-G it's just like that, only much, much worse!
在失重的时候和那个很像，就是更糟糕而已
Oh, too much information.
信息量太大了
Anyway, we're now officially sold out.
反正现在全都卖光了
Except of this one box of self-sealing stem bolts.
只剩下这一盒自封式螺栓（《星际迷航》的梗）
Oh, and Sina still needs to come and pick up the rest of her pudding.
哦对了，西娜还得过来把剩下的布丁拿走
The rest?
剩下的？
Three containers.
三个集装箱
Did she at least take the bomb off the ship?
她就不能先把炸弹挪走吗？
Of course!
当然！
Did you check?
你检查过了吗？
Trust me, I'm an expert, okay?
相信我，我是个专家，好吗？
Famous last words!
最著名的遗言！
You don't trust people easily, do you?
你从不轻信别人对吗
Childhood trauma, my standard excuse.
问起来就是童年创伤
Sure.
行吧
How about Sina, do you trust her?
西娜呢，你相信她吗？
Not as far as I could throw her, with gravity on.
重力一开，我扔不动她
She's definitely one of the good guys!
她肯定是个好人！
But she wants to drop a bomb on Earth
但她想往地球上扔炸弹
And Earth tried to drop a bomb on us!
地球还想给我们扔炸弹呢！
It's not like either of us are ever going to return.
反正我们俩也不可能再回去了
Sorin, my friends and family are on Earth.
索林，我的朋友和家人都在地球上！
I don't belong here. I...
我不属于这里，我……
I feel so incredibly lonely and homesick right now
我现在感觉特别孤独，也特别想家
I cried myself to sleep last night, and...
我昨晚都是哭着睡着的……
I'm... I'm sorry.
对……对不起
And think of all the innocent people that are going to die!
想想那些无辜的人都要死去！
The world will never be the same.
世界将永远不同！
We can't let that happen!
我们绝不能让这件事发生！
So, what are you going to do?
所以，你准备做什么？
Rat her out?
把她出卖了？
Of course not!
当然不是！
The Pioneers are my life insurance right now.
开拓者现在是我的保险
But that doesn't mean I have to agree with them
但这不代表我就必须认可
Nuking my home planet.
往我家乡扔核弹
You're still thinking like an Earther.
你还是像地球人一样思考
That's why you don't get it.
所以你没理解到
That there is nothing left on Earth for us to love
我们在地球上已经没有留念了
Is the reason why we all became pioneers in the first place!
这是我们成为开拓者的首要条件
But what if there is something left on Earth that she still loves?
万一地球上还有她爱的呢？
Look here.
看这个
What's that?
这是什么？
I used some of my old connections and did some research.
我用我以前的账号做了下功课
Sina Stillwater entering sick leave
西娜·斯蒂尔沃特请病假
June 20th, 2324
2324年6月20号
ERG Davida, mining operations...
ERG戴维达矿产项目……
I thought we knew all that already?
我觉得我们已经知道了
Scroll down.
往下滑
Albio Sengo went back to Earth for emergency neurological treatment...
阿尔比奥·森戈回地球接受紧急神经治疗……
What's the point?
那又咋？
Look at the date!
看日期！
Scheduled for shuttle transport June 21st, 2324...
飞船启航日期2324年6月21日
What?
什么？
He went down to Earth hospital the day after Sina's procedure?
就在西娜手术后一天，他去地球上接受治疗了？
Isn't that peculiar?
这是不是很奇怪？
Well, it's the bloody ERG
那可是他妈的ERG
Their records are wrong all the time!
我们的记录总是有错！
I've been in this business long enough to know when I'm onto something.
我干这行久了，自然知道什么时候抓到重要线索
The business of making people believe your stories so they do what you want?
哪行？让人相信你的故事，然后按你的想法做事？
I prefer to call it journalism
这就是新闻学魅力时刻
Albiel was taken to Earth and that's the place I know my way around.
阿尔比奥被带回了地球，那地方我最熟悉
If he's still there, we can find him!
如果他还在那里，我们就能找到他！
You mean you can find him.
不，是你去找到他！
Because I am going home with my wife and kids.
因为我要回家，老婆孩子热炕头
Plant my lazy ass on the sofa
往沙发上一躺
and stay in precisely that position for at least half a year!
至少半年不起来
Aren't you going to resume your work as a freight carrier pilot?
你不打算继续做货运飞行员吗？
Maybe eventually.
可能以后吧
Take me to Earth, and I'll give you...
把我带去地球，我会给你……
This ship!
这艘船！
What?
怎么了？
That's a good one!
这个笑话不错！
If that's the price for your half of this rust bucket, feel free to keep it!
如果是你这半艘破船的价钱，随便你，拿去吧！
I can't take you on Earth on a stolen ship, not even close!
我用偷来的船带你回地球？根本不可能！
And who says Sina's going to let you go anyway?
再说了，西娜怎么会放你走？
Well, let's see what she has to say about this
行吧，那我们看看她怎么说……
May I?
试试？
Hi!
好啊
Oh, hey!
嗷，你好啊
Hey, Lyra!
你好，莱拉！
I know, I totally forgot about the rest of the pudding.
我知道，我把剩下的布丁都忘了！
I really forgot about it.
我确实是忘了
I will send someone to pick the pudding up right away.
我现在就派人去把布丁拿回来
Yes, very good, but that's not why I'm calling.
行，很好，但这不是我打电话的原因
Oh, what is it then?
行，那是什么事情？
I thought you might want to have a look at this document.
我想你可能对这份文件有兴趣
Sending now.
正在传输
Oh, ok.
嗯，好
Who?
谁？
Wait, Lyra, you are kidding me!
等等，莱拉，你在消遣我吗？
You're making this up, aren't you?
这都是你编出来的吧？
Check the flight database, the dates match.
去看下飞行数据库，日期是对得上的
We can't talk about this online.
我们不能在网上说这件事
I'm near the dock. Hang on, I'm coming over.
我在对接口这边，稍等，马上过来
I knew she'd bite.
我就知道她会上钩
You tricky bitch!
你个心机婊！
Well, I'm not forcing her to do anything.
我又没强迫她
I'm just telling the truth.
只是和她摆事实
And if it works, it'll be a win-win-win.
要是成功了，那就是秦始皇踩电线——赢麻了
I get back to Earth, she gets her lover back
我回地球，她找到爱人
And every day she's not here is one more day she can't drop the bomb.
只要她不在这，就没人扔炸弹
A visitor is requesting entry.
有访客请求进入
How? That was fast.
怎么可能？这也太快了！
You little trash panda!
你个垃圾小熊猫！（《银河护卫队》的梗）
Where did you get this and why have you been snooping on me?
这东西哪来的？为什么追着我不放？
I found a back door to ERG's payroll database.
我找到ERG薪资数据库的后门了
Do you even realize what this means to me?
你知道这对我来说有多重要吗？
What Albio means to me?
阿尔比奥对我而言有多重要吗？
That is nothing to joke about!
这事容不得玩笑！
I'm taking it dead seriously.
这要是假的我天打五雷轰！
Again, why have you been snooping on me?
还有，你为什么追着我不放？
She wants to go back to Earth, and she hopes you will somehow make this happen.
她想回地球，想让你帮她能弄成这件事
Is that true?
真的吗？
Yes.
是
No, I mean, sort of, but it's not the whole truth.
不，我的意思是，有一些吧，但不全是
I hate it when people are trying to play games with me!
我很讨厌别人逗我玩！
Sina, if Albio is still alive on Earth, I'm sure we can find him for you
西娜，如果阿尔比奥还在地球上，我觉得我们一定能帮你找到
If only I could get there...
只要我能到那里……
That sounds too good to be true.
说的和真的似的
It's just an offer, you decide.
我只是提议，决定权在你那里
Fair enough.
挺合理的
In fact, I just had an idea.
实际上，我有个想法
Yes, I think I know a way to make this worthwhile.
我想，我有办法让这趟旅行值回票价
Oh, that's great!
啊，太棒啦！
But you're not going to go anywhere without me.
但你必须跟着我
We will be in this together.
我们要一直待在一起
If I get the slightest hint of you trying to fool me
如果我觉得你在耍心眼
I am going to bite your head off!
那我就会把你的头铲飞！
U ... understood.
明……明白了！
I am going to be the captain of this flight.
我要当这次航行的舰长
And Sorin is going to be the pilot.
索林来当飞行员
No fucking way!
门儿都没得！
You are the only one I can trust enough for this.
你是我唯一一个信得过的
Did we really just go from 'is this even real'
我们真的从‘这是真的假的’
to 'lets go to Earth' in less than five seconds?
一下子就跳到‘走吧回地球’了吗？不到五秒？
I said no fucking way!
不去，我坚决不去！
So we will have to take this ship to Link Kabanshee to get it rebadged.
我们得把飞船开到林克·卡班希那里换个马甲
Link owes Sorin big time.
林克欠了索林一大笔人情！
Link Kabanshee?
林克·卡班希？
That guy is a madman, he is going to kill me!
那是个他妈的疯子，他会杀了我的！
Come with me, Sorin.
索林，来这边一下
Let me make you an offer... just between us.
我给你开个条件……只有我们两个人知道
Lyra, if you would excuse us for a moment?
莱拉，让我们两个好好谈一谈吧
Is anybody listening to me?
有人在听我说吗？
No, is it only over my dead body! Aaaaaa!
不，除非从我的尸体上踏过去！啊啊啊！
I love politics!
办公室的瓜真好吃！
Ok computer, start recording. Chapter one, page one.
电脑，开始录音，第一章，第一页
Affirmative.
收到
As a community of Earth dwelling species, the sheer scale of space defies our senses.
作为地球生物，太空的浩瀚超越了我们的感官
On Earth, a full moon sometimes looks close enough
在地球上，一轮满月有时看起来很近
to reach out and grab, sitting low on the horizon.
低挂在地平线上，仿佛伸手可及
But our worldly perception deceives us.
但我们的世俗感知欺骗了我们
Just a century ago, bridging the airless chasm between Earth and its moon
就在一个世纪前，跨越地球与月球之间，那条无气的鸿沟
barely 230,000 miles wide, took years of preparation.
仅仅二十三万英里宽，都需要多年的准备
And the pioneer who risked his life to set a paw on its surface
而那个冒着生命危险，第一次把爪子踏上其表面的开拓者
for the first time became a national hero.
成了国家英雄
Fast forward to the world of today, where a trip
快进到今天
to the moon is little more than a casual vacation.
去月球旅行不过是一次随意的度假
People long to see the Earth from space the way
人们渴望从太空看地球
people used to long to see the ocean in ancient times.
正如古人渴望看海洋
The final frontier has moved away from Earth a thousandfold.
边疆已经远离地球千百倍
Here, not 200,000, but 300 million miles
在离家不再是二十万，而是三亿英里的地方
from home, is where I met with the pioneers of today.
我遇到了当今的开拓者
The only way you get to experience these vast
你体验这些浩瀚距离唯一的方式就是
distances is by the time it takes to travel them.
花费旅行的时间
Due to the absence of a day and night cycle, which we have evolved to follow
由于缺乏我们进化适应的昼夜循环
As well as the relativistic nature of space and time
再加上时空的相对性
your grasp on the passage of time will fail you sooner or later.
你迟早会失去对时间流逝的把握
We're going to be arriving soon at the decommissioned ERG transport hub
我们马上就要抵达那座已退役的 ERG 运输枢纽
owned by the system's most notorious criminal.
它归本星系里最臭名昭著的罪犯所有
And I've already lost track of how long it's been.
而我早已记不清到底航行了多久
A day feels like a week, a week feels like an eternity.
一天像一周，一周像永恒
But wild horses couldn't drag me back into the cryo chamber I nearly died in.
但就算野马也没法将我拖回差点杀死我的冷冻舱里
Computer, stop recording.
电脑，停止录音
Oh, sorry, I didn't mean to disturb you. The door wasn't locked, so I...
对不起，我不是故意打扰你的，门没锁，所以我就……
No, no, it's fine. I'm just trying to pass the time.
不，没关系，我只是想打发时间
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
Just recording my thoughts.
只是记录下我的想法
I'm trying to make sense of everything.
我在努力让一切都变得有意义
If I survive this, maybe I can turn it into a book.
如果我能活下来，我想把这段经历写成一本书
Once a journalist, always a journalist!
一日为记者，终身为记者！
I'm just thinking ahead!
我只是在为未来做准备！
I lost everything. I'm going to need a way to earn some money when I'm back on Earth.
我失去了一切，回到地球后总得有个吃饭的家伙
You really are an incurable optimist.
你真是个不可救药的乐观主义者
You can be happy if they don't ship you right back to Vesta.
不被直接送回维斯塔，就不错了！
Did you just come here to tell me that? Or is there something else?
你是专门来告诉我这个的吗？还是有别的事？
Dinner's ready.
晚饭好了
Let me guess, Beans and Franks?
让我猜猜，豆子加热狗？
No, today is mac and cheese day!
不，今天是芝士通心粉日！
On our next trip, I'll do the groceries!
下次出远门我来备菜！
What's wrong with mac and cheese?
芝士通心粉有什么不好？
Nothing.
没什么
How can you not like mac and cheese? Mac and cheese is the best!
你怎么会不喜欢芝士通心粉？芝士通心粉是最棒的！
Yeah, but not five times a week!
确实，但不能一周吃五次啊！
Especially five times a week!
尤其是一周五次！
Computer, please put me back into cryosleep.
电脑，请把我送回冷冻舱
Unable to comply. Service code 4879
无法执行，服务代码4879
Uh great, and another interruption.
呃，行吧，又来打断我工作
Hello, can I help you?
你好，我能帮你些啥？
Yeah, my name is Sorin Jax.
你好，我是索林·贾克斯
I'd like to talk to Link Kabanshee, please.
我想和林克·卡班西聊聊可以吗？
Is it something you need?
有什么需要做的吗？
Yeah, well, it's a little software update we... we need to do, and...
嗯，这是我们需要一个小软件更新，然后……
Well, I've sent a message, he should be expecting me.
我给他发过消息了，他应该知道我要来……
We're old friends
我们是老朋友了
Friends? Are you certain?
朋友？你确定吗？
Yes, we've known each other for years!
当然，我们认识好多年了！
Can you please call him?
你能联系下他吗？
Alright, I'll see he's in the right mood.
好吧，希望他现在心情正好
Shit! Not in the right mood! Not in the right mood!
草了！他心情不好！他心情不好！
Sorin, Lyra, take cover!
索林，莱拉，快找掩体！
No, Sina, it's fine, I'll handle this.
不用，西娜，还好啦，我能处理
Hey Link, old buddy, good to see you!
好啊，林克老兄，好久不见！
You got some nerve showing up here like this, you son of a bitch!
敢这样跑到这儿来，算你有种，龟儿子！
Link, can we please just talk?
林克，我们能不能好好谈谈？
And may I remind you that we are inside a pressurized cabin in the middle of space!
提醒你一下，我们可是身处太空的一个加压舱内！
Oh, for fuck's sake!
呵，锤子个铲子
Brian? Brian!
布莱恩？布莱恩！
Come here and put some tape on that hole, will ya?
去给那个洞拿胶带粘上！
Hurry up, Brian! Hop, hop, hop, hop!
快点，布莱恩！加速！加速！
Now come out and tell me what you want, you coward!
现在出来，说下你们想要干嘛！软脚虾！
Hey Link, it's me, Sorin!
林克，是我，索林！
The guy who saved your life, remember?
我救了你的命，你还记得吗？
Of course I remember you, my hero!
当然记得，大英雄！
It was 15 fighter ships against us two!
十五架战斗机打我们两个
Yes.
当然
And they would be my fighter ships now
如果你不来救我的话
if you hadn't decided to save me, fucking idiot!
那十五架战斗机就是我的了！傻X
Better let me do the talking.
还是我来说吧
No, no, I can handle this!
不用，不用，我能处理！
Hi, we have got this nice new ship out there.
我们外头有艘超巴适的新船哦！
Unfortunately, we're in trouble with the previous owner
很不幸，我们和它的前主人有点过节
and we need our ID transponder changed.
而且我们需要更换我们的身份应答器
My lady, you do know that's highly illegal, don't you?
女士，您知道这个是非法的吧？
Yeah, the moment I came here I knew we would fit right in.
就是！我一到这儿来，就晓得我们肯定合得来！
Re-batching some old space taxi, that's one thing.
把一艘旧太空出租车重新改装，那倒是小事一桩
What you've got out there is a brand new Rhino Mark IV
你弄来的是一艘全新的犀牛马克四飞船
that will require some special attention.
那可得特别注意了
And even if it works, it's so new and shiny
就算弄好的，你的飞船也是新得发亮
it will stick out like a sore thumb wherever you go!
就像人群中的光头一样！
So, can you do it?
所以，你能接活吗？
The question is not if I can do it. The question is, can you afford it?
问题不是我做不做得到，而是你们付得起钱吗？
My lady, you are my new favorite customer!
女士，您现在是我最爱的客户了！
Brian! Get the data cable and the Rhino adapter, we've got some work to do.
布莱恩！把数据线和适配器准备好，我们来活儿啦！
Brian do this, Brian do that, next time you're putting your socks on yourself!
布莱恩干这个，布莱恩干那个，下次你自己穿袜子去吧！
What?
你说啥？
Get me clear, eh?
听懂了吗，老登？
Christically!
老天爷啊！
We'll have to make a backup with your main computer, perform a complete memory wipe
我们必须备份主电脑，进行彻底的内存擦除
and then reinstall it with a new identity.
然后把它重装一遍，换个新身份
In order to do that, the entire ship must be completely powered down.
在这期间整艘飞船必须完全关机
Including the reactor?
包括反应堆吗？
Especially the reactor.
尤其是反应堆！
Alright, I'll take care of that, you'll be able to reach me through my comms.
好吧，我来处理，你可以用通讯器联系我
So, how long is this going to take?
这个大概要花多久？
Ahh, not long. Getting nervous outside of your little comfort zone?
啊，不会太久的
What do you mean?
你是什么意思？
I know who you are, and you are not exactly known
我知道你是谁，斯蒂尔沃特夫人
for leaving your ivory tower, 'Mrs. Stillwater'.
你可不是那种会走出来的人啊
Yes, me being out here better stays our little secret, 'Mr. Kabanshee'.
是啊，我在这里这件事最好还是我们的小秘密，卡班希先生
Do I look like I want to paint a huge red target on my ass?
你觉得我会自找麻烦吗？
We have more customers incoming, Link.
林克，有更多客人来了
Are you sure? I'm not expecting anyone.
你确定吗？我没收到消息
What kind of ship?
什么样子的船？
I can't say yet. They're not transmitting an ID
我还不知道，他们还没上传身份
and they're not close enough for anything visual
而且还没进入目视范围！
I hate it when people come in without warning!
我真讨厌这些不打招呼就上门的！
Send them to pad B, and no service until we know
把他们送到B舱，等我们搞清楚他们是谁
who they are and what they want, you hear me?
想来干啥，再接待，听到了吗？
As always.
一直都能
Sina, you getting me?
西娜，能听到我吗？
Yep
能
Reactor's powered down, computer's in recovery mode.
反应堆已经关闭，电脑处于恢复模式
Alright, Brian's gonna start the upload now.
好，布莱恩会开始上传程序
Don't touch anything!
别乱摸！
If the transfer gets interrupted, your CPU is going to be one expensive piece of trash.
如果传输被中断，你的CPU可就成一块昂贵的垃圾了
Gotcha.
收到
Link, the ship's not answering, anything in mind?
林克，对方没有答复，你有思路吗？
Hail them one more time, then set off some fireworks.
再发送一次，不回话就给他们放个烟花
Very well.
好的
Sounds like there is trouble brewing.
听起来有麻烦了
Nah, not really. Every few months some idiot thinks
还行吧，每隔几个月，就会有一群蠢货觉得
just because we're not under Earth law, they can raid us like the local 7-11.
没有地球法律，就能把我这里当711抢劫
We are well prepared for that.
我们早就做好了战斗准备
What the hell's going on out there?
外面发生什么？
Just some unregistered ship getting too close.
有些未注册的船靠太近了
Until the update's done, we're deaf, blind and completely defenseless.
在更新完成前，我们就是一群小聋瞎
How far are we?
目前进度如何了
20%
20%
What the fuck was that?
那他妈又是啥？
I will try to find out, just hang in there!
我会试着搞明白的，保持通话！
Alright!
好的
It's a freaking M-class Yellowjacket!
这是个他妈的M级大黄蜂！
No external markings, and they're melting our turrets!
没外部标记，他们正在融掉我们的炮塔！
Fuck, that's no ordinary raid.
娘希匹，这可不是一般打劫的
Oh great!
得了吧！
They're preparing to land on Pad C!
他们准备降落在C舱！
Sound the alarm and batten down the hatches.
拉响警报！关闭舱门
If they want to talk, we will talk.
要谈就谈
If they try to invade, initiate Sequence Red.
要打的话，就按照红色预案
Sequence Red?
红色预案？
Yes, Sequence Red.
对，红色预案！
Who are these people?
这些到底是什么人？
I don't know, and I don't want to find out!
我不知道，我也不关心
Sorin, come in!
索林，接电话！
What's going on down there?
上面发生什么事了？
The station is being attacked by an unmarked fighter ship.
空间站在被一架没有标识的战斗机攻击！
We need to get out of here ASAP!
我们得立刻撤退！
How far is the upload?
上传进度如何了？
30%
30%
Thirty? Oh shit!
才30%，完逑了
Who's the target, the station or us?
谁是目标？空间站还是我们？
I wish I knew.
我希望我知道
Link, what's Sequence Red?
林克，红色预案是什么？
Evacuation, then self-destruction.
撤退然后自爆
Not gonna let anybody see the skeletons in my closet.
不能让他们发现我衣柜里的尸体
Can we postpone Armageddon until after our ship is back online, please?
我们能不能等飞船上线后，再来世界末日啊！
I think we have a touchdown.
我觉得我们被跳帮了
The ship has landed!
战斗机降落了！
Cargo bay just opened!
登陆舱刚刚打开！
People in armored suits are pouring out!
上面下来了好多武装分子！
20, 50, maybe 100!
20，50，可能有100人!
Ah shit, these guys aren't here for negotiations.
锤子，这群人不是来谈判的
Evacuate, evacuate, evacuate!
撤退，撤退，撤退！
Well, there goes the workshop...
哎，车间完蛋了……
Come on, follow me, this way!
来，跟着我，往这边走……
No, we have to make sure that the update gets through
不，我们必须要保证传输完成
Or Sorin will be stuck here with the enemy!
不然索林就得和敌人一起上天了！
Sorin, come in!
索林，快接电话！
Tell me the good news first.
我想先听好消息！
No good news, I'm afraid.
没有好消息
The station is being invaded.
空间站被跳帮了
The crew is evacuating.
乘员正在疏散
How far are we?
我们进度如何了吗？
40%
40%
Link, is it possible to hold this hangar for just a few more minutes?
林克，能不能让机库坚持几分钟？
This station is a workshop, not a bunker!
这个空间站是个车间，不是堡垒！
Freeze! Hands behind your head, now!
不许动！双手抱头！
Here, defend yourself!
拿着，保护自己！
Link, close the fire door, quick!
林克，快关闭防火门！
Shit, shit!
遭了，遭逑了！
Upload is at 50%
上传完成50%了
Oh, Link, how bad is it?
林克，伤情严重吗？
It's really bad!
非常严重！
I'm hearing strange noises through the hull.
我听到船舱里有奇怪的声音
I think they're trying to break in!
他们想闯进来！
What the hell are these guys even looking for?
这些家伙在他妈找什么？
They're not mucking around!
他们来真的了！
Lyra, put your helmet on, now!
莱拉，快把头盔戴上！
Upload is at 60%
上传60%了
Do you think you can make it back to the ship?
你觉得你能回到船上吗？
No idea!
不知道！
It's just a few meters, but no cover...
只有几米远，但没有掩护......
No! We're losing pressure!
不！我们失压了！
I... I can't breathe...
我……我不能呼吸……
Help me!
救救我！
Link, over there, the ATV!
林克，那边，全地形车
The what?
什么？
The exploration vehicle, it's got a pressurized cabin.
探测车，那上面有一个加压舱
It's a complete wreck, how do we know it's still sealed?
它已经完全损坏了，我们怎么知道它有没有密封？
Shut up and help me!
闭嘴，快来帮我！
Upload at 70%
上传进度70%
Sorin!
索林！
Yes?
我在
They're trying to bust through the airlock.
他们正试图冲破气闸
If that happens, we're going to make a run for it.
如果发生这种情况，我们就会立刻逃跑
Okay...
行……
I want you to open the cargo door as soon as possible.
我要你尽快打开舱门
What if anybody else gets in?
如果有其他人进来怎么办？
That's going to be the least of our problems, trust me!
我觉得这个不是最大的问题！
What about Link? Are we going to carry him?
林克怎么办？我们要带着他吗？
Our first priority is to secure the computer and get away
我们的首要任务是确保计算机的安全
But we can't just leave him here! Does the vehicle still work?
但我们不能把他留在这里，车还能用吗？
80%
80%
It's got a new motor, but no main reactor.
它有一个新的电机，但没有主反应堆
Then tell me where I can find one!
那就告诉我在哪里能找到！
Lyra?
莱拉？
Lyra, look for exploration equipment that's often built to be power independent.
莱拉，去找能独立供电的勘探设备
Something, like the thing up there?
就像上面那个东西？
Sorin, what do you say?
索林，你觉得呢？
Hold your camera still.
稳住你的相机
What?
什么？
No, no, that's way too big, you could power a small ship with that.
不，那太大了，它都可以为一艘小飞船提供动力了
That means it's perfect!
这意味着它是完美的！
What?
什么？
Alright.
好了
Now.
现在
Crane moving left...
起重机向左移……
Yeah...
好……
Okay, okay, okay
就这样
And stop!
停！
Down...
向下……
Is here...
就是这里……
Okay...
好……
Okay, catching on!
勾住了！
Okay.
好
And...
然后……
Moving to the right...
向右移动……
Come on...
来吧……
Does it work?
行吗？
Okay...
好……
Yeah, okay, slowly...
好，很好，慢一点……
Slowly...
慢一点……
Fuck!
卧槽！
That was the outer door of the airlock!
那是气闸的外门！
One more blast and they are through!
再炸一下，他们就进来了！
Get in the car, Lyra, quick!
莱拉，快上车！
Upload at...
上传……
99%
99%
It stopped moving at fucking 99%
他妈的卡在99%了！
Come on, you piece of shit!
快点，你这坨垃圾！
Load, load, load, load!
快快快！
I need more time to load the crane!
我需要更多时间来操作！
I need more time, Sina!
西娜，我需要更多时间！
Just drop the thing!
把它放下来！
On 3, 2, 1, now!
3，2，1，就是现在
Quick!
快！
100%!
100%!
Powering on!
开机！
Step on it for fuck's sake!
给我踩到底啊！妈的！
Whoa, hello!
嗨，你好啊！
Holy shit, what the hell was that?
卧槽，那他妈是啥！
Yes, yes, what is it?
是的，怎么了？
Sergeant Baker, this is Ricky Maturo.
贝克中士，我是里奇·马图罗
I'm on sentry duty.
我正在执勤
We have an anomaly!
我们发现了一个异常！
Yeah, I know who you are.
是的，我知道你是谁
What kind of anomaly?
什么样的异常？
Transient electromagnetic disturbance of magnitude
瞬态电磁干扰
F5+, followed by a hell of a gamma ray burst.
强度F5+，随后伴随强烈的伽马射线爆发
That's a doozy.
那可真猛
What's the location?
地点在哪里？
Blast was so strong, it's bouncing all over the place.
爆炸太强，信号到处反弹
I've tasked the deep space network to help cut through the reflections and triangulate.
我已经让深空网络帮忙过滤反射信号并进行三角定位
And that's confirmed, sector 4489
定位确认，发生在 4489 区域
Man, that was fast.
天啊，这速度也太快了
Did one of our ships report in?
我们有哪艘船报告情况了吗？
No, no, we don't have a mandate for that area.
没有，我们没有该区域的管辖权
It's the wild, wild west out there.
那片区域就是荒野大镖客啊
No, everyone in the system saw this, whatever it was.
不，系统里每个人都看到了，不管那是什么
Must have been spectacular!
肯定很壮观！
Well, if someone's drive blew up, you bet it was.
如果有人动力源爆炸，那绝对够壮观的
Oh, you're thinking engine detonation?
哦，你是说引擎爆炸？
Well, let's see.
嗯，让我看看
Closest match is a decommissioned ERG transport hub
最接近的记录是一座已退役的 ERG 运输枢纽
Registered to Dynamo Trading Limited.
注册在Dynamo贸易公司旗下
Man, that's Link Kabanshee!
天啊，那就是林克·卡班希！
Who's that now?
谁？
I keep forgetting, you're pretty new here.
我老忘了，你刚来不久
Link Kabanshee's a legend.
林克·卡班希是个传奇人物
Stinking rich, and... kind of a wild one.
他富得流油，而且……有点疯狂
After the station's decommissioning, the sector lost its controlled space status
在空间站退役后，该区域不再是受控空间
And, well, he saw that as a perfect opportunity to set up his own personal tax haven.
他就把这当成机会，建立自己的私人避税天堂
Well, in that case, it's a miracle he didn't get blown up earlier.
那样的话，他早就该被炸了才对
Hm, you'd think so, huh?
嗯，你会这么想吧？
Well, he's got a lot of friends in high places
他在高层有很多朋友
And, you know, according to his reputation, he's pretty much untouchable.
而且，根据他的名声，他几乎是不可碰的
Uh, if these records are still up to date
如果这些记录还是最新的话
His reactor's been due for replacement for five years!
他的反应堆五年前就该更换了！
Well, there you have it.
那就这样吧
Maybe we're just overthinking the whole issue.
也许我们想多了
Could have just been an accident.
这可能只是个意外
Oh, it's going to be an interesting investigation, that's for sure!
这肯定会是一场有趣的调查！
Uh, what investigation?
什么调查？
There's a nuclear explosion in space, and we're not going to investigate?
太空里发生了核爆，我们就不调查吗？
Heh, like you said, rookie:
呵，就像你说的，菜鸟：
Wild, wild west.
荒野大镖客
Where you're pretty much free to blow yourself up as you wish.
你几乎可以随心所欲地自爆
The investigation bureau's just going to look at the data
调查局只会看数据
Confirm the nature of the explosion
确认爆炸性质
And that's pretty much it.
仅此而已
I mean, what are we supposed to do?
我的意思是，我们能做什么？
There's nothing left to look at
那里什么都没剩下
And if there's no one there to be rescued
如果没人需要救援
It's not really our job to waste any tax money on it.
我们也没必要浪费纳税人的钱
That's the whole point of uncontrolled space.
这就是非受控空间的意义所在
Uh, hold up, sir, I'm picking up a ship leaving the area.
等等，长官，我捕捉到一艘船正在离开该区域
SpaceX, Rhino, Mark IV
SpaceX 犀牛马克四型
They've responded to hails on CommNet
他们回应了CommNet的呼叫
And they say they're fine.
他们说没事
They claim they're about to deliver
他们声称要交付
Some chocolate pudding?
一些巧克力布丁？
Whatever the hell that's code for.
不知道那是什么暗号
Got struck by some shrapnel
被一些未知碎片击中
But it scraped some paint, nothing more.
但只是刮伤了点漆，没大事
Heh, chocolate pudding?
呵，巧克力布丁？
Right, okay.
嗯，好吧
Well, whatever.
无论如何
I wouldn't be surprised if Link himself is on that ship.
我不会感到惊讶，如果林克本人就在那艘船上
You think we'll ever find out?
你觉得我们能知道吗？
Eh, probably not
嗯，可能不会
And it's not really our business anyway.
而且这也不关我们的事
Let's just file the report and be done with it.
就把报告备案就行了
Understood, sir.
明白，长官
Ricky Maturo out.
里奇·马图罗，完毕
Hey, didn't your mom teach you any manners?
你妈没教你，做人要有礼貌吗？
Nope!
没！
Oh, stop it, that's disgusting!
停一下吧，太下头了！
In space, nobody can hear you belch.
在太空中，没人能听到你打嗝
Yeah, just wait.
对，等会儿
Just wait until we enter the control zone.
等我们进入控制空间再说吧
Under Earth legislation, manners are strictly enforced.
在地球上，你是要讲文明的！
Ha! Maybe.
切！可能吧
But first they gotta catch me.
但他们得先抓住我！
Do you hear me, Earthlings?
听到了吗，地球人？
The pioneers are coming!
我狐汉三又回来啦！
Stop, stop, stop, guys, guys
停停停，伙计们！
This might be important, okay?
接下来的事情很重要，好吗！
Ah, we are about to enter control space.
我们快进入受控空间了
I'll be on the bridge getting us checked in.
我会在舰桥为我们办理登记
Keep your claws crossed they'll let us.
你们祈祷他们让我们进去吧
They will.
他们肯定会
Your new certificates should be cryptographically
你的新证书应该在密码学上与真证书无法区分！
Let's hope so, by goodness!
但愿如此，老天保佑！
I would bet my station on it if I still had one.
我会拿我的空间站保证，如果我还有的话
Well, I'm still amazed how easy you're taking your loss.
我挺吃惊的，你对自己的损失如此坦荡
Well, I knew I might have to blow it up eventually
其实吧，我总觉得最后得亲手炸掉空间站
Why would I install a self-destruct if I wasn't prepared to use it?
如果不这么想，我为什么要安装自毁装置？
You are a lot richer than you look, aren't you?
你比看上去要有钱得多，不是吗？
It's a bit more complicated than that...
其实这个挺复杂的……
Oh, is it?
是吗？
I could tell you, but then I would have to blow your ship up too.
我可以给你说，但在那之后我要把你的船也炸掉
And what happens with your business now?
你的生意怎么办呢？
Ah, we will have to relocate.
这个，我们得换地方了
No shit.
就这？
The workshop was just a fancy branch office.
车间只是一个豪华的分部办公室
The stuff that really brings in the money is all digital.
真正赚钱的东西都是数字化的
And I have more than just one backup, believe me.
相信我，我的备份不止一个
Any idea who attacked us?
你觉得是谁攻击了我们？
Nope.
不知道
Some kind of UN black ops?
某种联合国秘密行动？
I don't think so.
我不觉得是
The military has been secretly buying spare parts from me for ages.
军方一直在偷偷找我购买备件
We always had a great relationship.
我们关系一直不错
Could it have anything to do with us?
这个可能和我们有关吗？
Sina, who else knows you're on this ship?
西娜，还有谁知道你在这艘船上？
Nobody, I swear.
没其他人，我发誓
Maybe they were after Trent Binkin.
也许他们的目标是特伦特·宾金？
But he's dead.
但他已经死了啊
Well, all they know is that the ship left Juno Station and the bomb didn't explode.
他们只知道飞船离开了朱诺空间站，而且炸弹没有爆炸
Wait a minute, who is Trent Binkin?
等下，谁是特伦特·宾金？
Who are they and what bomb didn't explode?
他们是谁？什么炸弹没爆炸？
He's a secret agent sent by Earth who tried to smuggle a fucking
他是地球派来的秘密特工，试图偷运一个他妈的
SDC-4 anti-matter bomb onto my station
SD-Z4反物质炸弹到我的地盘上
SD?
SD?
Stillwater Dynamics?
斯蒂尔沃特动力？
Yeah, isn't it ironic?
对，这个很搞笑吧？
It has my goddamn family name on it!
老娘的姓在上面
With love from mom.
来自妈妈的爱
That really doesn't mean anything.
这并不意味着什么
It narrows it down to a UN source at the very least.
这至少将范围缩小到了联合国
What happened to that Binkin guy again?
那个叫宾金的家伙又怎么了？
I shot the motherfucker.
我毙了他狗日的！
The defenseless motherfucker!
手无寸铁，狗日的
Hey, which side are you on?
喂，你到底站哪边？
He wanted to kill us all!
他想把我们都送走呢！
And now we're never going to know who sent him!
现在我们永远也不知道是谁派他来的了！
Did he carry any ID?
他有什么身份证吗？
What, like his secret secret agent travel passport?
什么，他的秘密特工旅行护照吗？
I got his tablet, but it's encrypted.
我拿到了他的平板，但被加密了
Latest gen. Tried everything, it's hopeless.
最新一代，什么都试过了，都不行
Can I see it?
我能看看吗？
Uh sure.
好啊
Can you get me a diagnostics cable? There is something I want to try.
你能给我一根检测线吗？我想试一下
Yeah, sure, hang on.
好啊，稍等
What are you going to do?
你打算怎么办？
Why, unlock this thing of course.
当然是解锁这个东西
But how?
怎么做啊？
Do you think the UN would allow personal devices they can't unlock?
你认为联合国会允许无法解锁的个人设备吗？
I always thought it was just a conspiracy theory.
我一直以为这只是一种阴谋论
Just because you're not paranoid doesn't mean they're not after you.
你不多疑，不代表他们没在盯着你
Here, there you go.
找到了
Thank you!
谢谢！
The Bangenator version 93.332 is licensed under the GPL V12
Bangenator 93.332 版在 GPL V12 下授权
Let's see...
先试试吧……
Scanning for passwords...
正在扫描密码……
Access denied.
禁止访问
Damn it!
草了！
Scanning for passwords...
正在扫描密码……
Maybe like this...
或许像这样……
Device unlocked.
设备解锁
Oh, it's that easy? Holy crap!
啊？就这？
Alright...
好了……
Now...
现在……
Show me your address book and I will tell you who you are.
只要找到通讯录，我就知道你是谁
Let's see...
这……
Not much on here...
没多少信息……
No personal contacts, only a few proxy addresses.
没有私人联系方式，只有几个代理地址
Ship maintenance software, crypto stuff...
舰船维护软件，密码相关的东西……
Maps, location history starts on Earth.
地图，位置记录从地球开始
This thing is still online!
这玩意儿居然还在线！
And we just got a message.
还能收到消息！
From First National Credit.
来自第一国民信贷
A chargeback!
一笔退款！
"We are sorry to inform you that our system has detected a fraudulent transaction."
“很遗憾地通知您，我们的系统检测到一笔欺诈交易”
Wow, that's quite a sum!
哇，真他妈有钱！
Initiated by some Attila B. Shamir.
发起人是某个阿提拉·B·沙米尔
It might be probably too late, but maybe you should take the tablet off the network
我可能说的有点晚了，我觉得你应该先断开网络
Oh shit, they could have been tracking us with this device all along.
他妈的，他们可能一直在用这个装置跟踪我们
Why didn't I think of this?
老娘怎么就没想到呢！
Typical beginner's mistake.
经典菜鸟作死
Now, who is Attila Shamir?
谁是阿提拉·沙米尔？
Oh, I know him!
嗷，我知道他
He's the Chief Security Officer at the Extraplanetary Resources Group.
他是星际资源集团的首席安全官
We used to be golf buddies.
我们以前一起打过高尔夫
What?
什么？
Yes, it's a long story.
对，那是很久之前的事了
So Binkin wasn't on the military's payroll, but on ERG's.
所以宾金不是军方的人，他是属于星际资源集团的
But does that make sense?
这合理吗？
We are not at war with the ERG!
我们又没和ERG打仗！
The worst thing we've ever done to them is squat a few derelict bases.
我们对他们做的最糟的事，就是抢了几个废弃的基地
Maybe it is time to change perspective.
也许是时候转换视角了
On Earth, you're not seen as much of a threat by anybody.
在地球上，你并不被任何人视为威胁
In the asteroid belt, however, it's a different situation.
然而，在小行星带，情况就不同了
Out there, ERG is not just a company.
在这里，ERG不只是一个公司
It's an empire built on the exploitation of cheap labor.
这是一个建立在剥削廉价劳动力基础上的帝国
And Juno Station is a socialist utopia in comparison.
对比之下，朱诺空间站则是一个理想的乌托邦
And their only competition is you.
他们唯一的竞争对手就是你
They've been pressuring the UN to strike against Juno for years without success
多年来，他们一直在向联合国施压
I wouldn't be surprised if they decided to take things into their own hands.
如果他们决定自己动手，我也不会感到惊讶
We are still Earth's most significant opposition.
对于地球而言，我们仍然是最大的敌人
Earth is more than just the UN.
地球又不止是联合国
Well, everyone is entitled to their own opinion.
每个人都有权发表自己的意见
Attention, we cleared the checkpoint and we're
注意，我们已经通过了检查站
now preparing to enter our assigned orbit.
现在正准备进入指定轨道
I want to keep our visit as short as possible.
我希望尽量缩短停留时间
So the next burn we'll pack a few more G's
下一次推进我们会增加几倍速度
Then our internal gravity can compensate for
我们的内部重力会有变化
So hold on to your drinks, over and out.
所以请抓好你的饮料，完毕
No matter what, we are in controlled space now.
无论如何，我们已经进入受控空间了
Whoever is after this ship can't attack us
不管是谁在追这艘船，都无法攻击我们
Without attracting a lot of unwanted attention.
不然只会招来关注
They might try to get at us personally
他们可能会对我们下手
But, well, that's a risk we'll have to take
但是，我们必须冒这个险
So let's go in and see if we can find Albio
我们进去看看能不能找到阿尔比奥
And get out again as fast as possible
并尽快离开
Where are we going to touch down?
我们要在哪里着陆？
Stockholm.
斯德哥尔摩
Nice!
真棒！
The Karolinska University Hospital in Stockholm to be precise.
准确地说，是斯德哥尔摩的卡罗林斯卡大学医院
It was the last known whereabouts of Albio Sengo
这是阿尔比奥·森戈最后的出现地点
After he was shipped from Davida for medical treatment.
在他被从戴维达运走接受治疗之后
And what is your plan?
那么你的计划呢？
Find out where he went from there...
看看他后来去了哪里……
You sound pretty confident.
我听起来很自信啊
I know how Earthers tick, trust me.
我知道地球人的尿性，相信我
There's almost nothing you can't find out
几乎没有你找不到的东西
With some good old social engineering.
只需要运用下古老的社会工程学知识
Social what?
社会啥？
Did you ever play pretend when you were little?
你小时候玩过家家吗？
It's a bit like that.
和那个类似
Of course, in fact, I've never quit playing it.
当然，事实上，我一玩就停不下来
I'm all in!
我很投入的！
I was way too busy becoming my foster parents'
我忙着成为养父母的完美玩具小兵人！
Wow, that was unexpected.
哇，真是出乎意料
Adopting me saved them from getting a birth license of their own.
收养了我，他们就不用去申请出生证了
The older I got, the more they treated me like I'm their property
我越长大，他们就越把我当成他们的财产
I'm sorry, I'm so happy to be finally home.
我很抱歉，我只是太激动能回家了
I forgot how different it is for you.
我忘了家对你有其他意义
I can't wait to be back on Earth.
我迫不及待地想回到地球
I could be in a different galaxy
我可以去其他星系
And I would still be closer to home than I am here!
我觉得那里比这里都像家
Sorry to interrupt your afternoon coffee
抱歉打扰你们的下午茶
I just got the time and coordinates for our shuttle.
我刚拿到我们的穿梭机的排班和位置
I hope you don't mind I'm not trying to land this unwieldy thing.
希望你们不要介意，我并不想降落这个笨重的东西
You'll have to go through immigration at the spaceport
我们必须在太空港办理入关手续
so keep your cryptographically indistinguishable certificates ready.
所以把你们在密码学上无法区分的证件准备好
Oh, and prepare for orbit insertion
准备进入轨道
In 4, 3, 2, 1, go!
4, 3, 2, 1, 开始！
Oh shit, here it comes.
我操，该来了……
This was so much easier when I still had a spine!
我的脊柱要是还在就好了！
Dr. Ilva, to the central sterile services Department.
伊尔瓦医生，请到中央消毒供应科报到
Dr. Ilva, please.
伊尔瓦医生
Okay, so, what was our plan again?
好了，我们现在准备怎么做？
The key to successful social engineering is to fit in.
成功进行社会工程的关键是融入环境
You have to make it look like you're the right
你必须让自己看起来像是
guy in the right place doing the right thing.
对的人在对的地方做对的事
And nobody will even question it!
没人会怀疑的！
So, the first thing you do is sit down and observe.
所以第一件事是，坐下来观察
Alright.
行吧
Dr. Ilva, to the central sterile services Department.
伊尔瓦医生，请到中央消毒供应科报到
Dr. Ilva, where the hell are you? We need you up here!
伊尔瓦医生，你他妈在哪儿，我们需要你！
Yes, yes, I'm coming, the bus was late, I'm sorry.
我来了，公交车晚点了，真是抱歉！
If you have seen Dr. Ilva, please send her to the central sterile services Department.
如果您见过伊尔瓦医生，请将她送到中央消毒供应科
Does anybody know if she still works at this place?
有人知道她还在这里工作吗？
Does this thing even work?
这玩意儿不会坏了吧？
Hello? Hello?
喂！喂！
I'm coming, for heaven's sake!
老天爷啊，我来了！
Hmm, very interesting.
哼哼，事情变得有趣起来了
Oh my god, we're losing him! Septic shock!
他快要死了！败血症休克！
Give him an amp of epi, a mig of atropine, 1.5 of each Erythro and Cefotaxime!
给他注射1单位肾上腺素，1 毫克阿托品
Get him into the trauma room! A04 is free!
把他送到A04抢救室！
What's going on?
发生什么事了？
He crashed!
他被撞了！
From bradycardic at 35 to flatline. Temp's 35.5.
患者心动过缓，心率 35 次/分，从心律停止到平线反应
We're stimulating his heart.
正在进行心脏起搏
Epi and atropine on board.
肾上腺素和阿托品已就绪
Any heart sounds?
心音？
Negative.
没有
Piggyback an Isuprel drip!
立即静脉滴注异丙肾上腺素
No, wait, I got a pulse.
等下，他有心跳了！
He's in V-tach.
患者出现室性心动过速
What the hell?
什么鬼！
Hold the Isuprel now, and give him Lidocaine!
停止异丙肾上腺素输注，立即静脉推注利多卡因
50 milligrams, IV push!
注射50毫克
His heart is racing!
他心跳加速！
Why?
为啥？
I don't know!
我不知道！
Let's get the 12-lead in there and see what's going on.
给他做一份 12 导联心电图，看看具体情况
Move it!
快！
What the?
什么鬼！
There we go, I've seen everything I need to see.
好了，该学的都学会了
Uh, whatever that might have been
呃，不管那是什么
You gotta look the part, act the part, and don't give them any time to think
你得看起来像那个角色，表现得像那个角色
And they'll even hold the door open for you.
他们就会给你开门！
You'll see!
你会明白的！
Now, do you think you can open one of those lockers for us?
你能帮我们打开一个储物柜吗？
Uh, sure.
呃，当然！
Let me have a look here...
让我看看……
There!
就这里了！
Then, let's get dressed.
好了，换衣服吧！
Oh, oh, jeez
嗷，啊，我去……
This is...
这他妈……
Ow, aw, can you get off my tail, please?
噢，噢，别踩我尾巴好吗？
Lyra, is that you?
莱拉，刚才那下是你吗？
Sina, could you give that back to me?
西娜，你能把那个还给我吗？
Is that your foot, Sorin, or is it your...
那是你的脚，还是你的……
Sorry, I thought it was mine.
不好意思，我以为那是我的……
What's this smoke?
这是什么烟味？
What's that on my back, jeez?
我的背上是什么，天啊！
This smells like someone had bean soup.
闻起来像是有人喝了豆汁
Sorin!
索林！
Ow, ow, ow
嗷嗷嗷
What are you doing there?
你在做么事？
Hey, careful with my tail, it was just attached!
嘿，小心我的尾巴，它才刚接上！
You...
你啊……
Hey, get your foot out of my face!
喂，把你脚从我脸上挪开！
And out of my nose, please.
还有我的鼻子，求你了！
That's not me!
那不是我！
Oh, Sina, it was your nose?
西娜，那是你的鼻子吗？
I thought it was your mouth, never mind.
我还以为是你的嘴，就这样吧
Yeah, how did you guess?
对啊，你怎么猜得到呢？
Let me get back up here...
让我先过去这里...
This is so tight!
这里真是挤死先人！
That's what she says.
她也这么说的！
Damn.
草
Are you guys coming?
你们能过来吗？
We're stuck!
我们被卡住了
What?
啥？
Yeah, we're stuck.
对，我们卡住了！
Move it, Lyra!
莱拉，快走！
We can't move.
我们动不了
Shit.
草
Come on, I'll help you.
来吧，我来帮你们
Alright
好了
Dr. Georgette Clooney, at your service.
乔治特·克鲁尼医生，为您服务
Oh, Dr. Clooney.
哇，克鲁尼医生
You look so competent it makes my appendix tingle.
您看起来太专业了，我的阑尾都要抖三抖
Oh, consider yourself lucky there wasn't a skeleton there.
哦，你该庆幸那里没有骷髅
Get your act together, guys.
各就各位
Alright, alright.
好的，好的
This is just too much fun right now.
到目前为止，这个太好玩了
Okay, next.
好了，下一步
We need someone to call Dr. Clooney over the PA
我们需要有人通过扩音机呼叫克鲁尼医生
So the nurse has heard my name before we come in.
这样护士能在我们进来前，听到我的名字
Link?
林克？
Oh, hey, Sina.
你好啊，西娜
Are you done yet?
你们办完事了吗？
We need some help!
我们需要点帮助！
And we need some help
我们需要点帮助
And this sounds like it's right up your alley.
在这方面你是专业的
Fire away!
来呗！
Can you hack into the hospital's PA system
你能黑进医院的广播系统吗？
and make an announcement that Dr. Clooney is urgently needed at the ICU?
广播重症监护室急需克鲁尼医生？
Who the fuck is Dr. Clooney?
谁几把是克鲁尼医生啊？
That doesn't matter!
这不重要！
Can you do it or not?
你到底能不能干！
I don't know...
我不知道……
Give me a few minutes, will ya?
能给我几分钟吗？
Uh-huh, thanks.
嗯哼，感谢
What the?
卧槽？
Hello?
听得见吗？
Oh, this was way too easy.
这个太简单了！
Dr. Clooney, Dr. Clooney
克鲁尼医生，克鲁尼医生
To the IT security department, please.
请赶快到信息安全部门！
Dr. Clooney, we have a breach.
克鲁尼医生，我们被黑了！
I don't believe it!
真是瞎逑闹！
Can't this man take anything seriously?
这老毕登太不正经了
Oh, you'd be surprised with the things I got away with in the past.
嗨，这有啥，林子大了什么鸟都有
He dropped the name, and that's good enough.
他至少报了名字，这就够了
Now all we need is a patient...
现在我们需要个病人……
Oh, and I already know who's precisely the right man for this!
我知道个绝佳的人选！
Hi, Link.
你好啊，林克
Hey, Sina.
你好啊，西娜
Back so soon?
这么快就回来啦！
Yeah, just come here.
我只是过来一下……
Hey...
等等……
I have a little idea...
让我看看……
Hey, hey, what?
喂喂，不要！
No!
杰哥不要啦！
So, are you coming?
你们要开始吗？
We're ready!
我们准备好了！
Hurry!
快！
Okay, everybody into position.
好了，各就各位
Remember, we've been doing this for years, and we know exactly what we're doing.
请记住，我们是专业的，我们非常清楚自己在做什么
On the count of three...
我数三下……
Three!
3！
The pain!
痛！
Oh, Dr. Clooney, what are we supposed to do now?
克鲁尼医生！我们要怎么做呢？
I think he has internal bleeding from the accident!
我觉得他可能在内出血！
Get me the number five G-Tube!
快给我五号胃管！
Now give me some suction!
快点吸
Give him 0.3 of WD40 and 0.6 of Kryptonite
给他0.3单位WD40和0.6单位氪石
and apply the nasal sponge!
给他鼻血堵上
Come on, don't leave us now!
坚持住，别洗白了啊
Skin PH 7.73 - slightly wrinkly!
皮肤PH值7.73，有点皱巴巴的
Heated rectal lavage?
热水灌肠？
What?
啥玩意儿啊？
No, his ass won't take it!
不行，他沟子遭不住的！
Hey you, I'm Dr. Clooney
喂喂，我是克鲁尼医生！
And this is my patient, Mr. Alvio Sengo
这是我的病人阿尔比奥·森戈先生
I need a copy of his patient record, stat!
我需要他的病历复印件，马上
Hey, what? Doctor who?
什么？胡医生？
No, Dr. Clooney, now give me that file!
不，克鲁尼医生，现在给我的文件！
Oh my god, it's melting!
完了，流进去了！
What's his temp?
他有多烧？
Temperature...
体温……
37.5
37.5
It's dribbling down my cheeks
都流到我沟子上了！
Hurry!
快点！
Oh my god, we are losing him!
完了，他快死逑了
All right, all right.
行啦，行啦
There's the file
文件在这里
But this is weird.
这也太怪了
Oh, what is weird? Let me see that!
有什么怪的？让我看看！
There we go...
我找到了……
Let's transfer that to my tablet.
正在上传到我的平板
Guys, I think we're in trouble
我想，我们遇到麻烦了
MIB coming at 3 o'clock!
特工从3点钟方向来了
I'm still connecting, one more second!
我正在连接，快了！
Hurry!
快点！
It's not pairing up!
还没对上呢！
Come on, come on, come on...
快点，快点，快点……
Shit, they saw us!
完了，他们看到我们了……
And done!
完事儿！
Okay, let's get out of here, quick!
好了，我们走吧，快点！
Into the ambulance, come on!
上救护车，快！
Come on, come on!
快点，快点！
Oh shit!
我日！
Have you seen this person?
你见过这个人吗？
Why yes, they went that way.
当然，他们从那边跑了！
The ambulance, they're getting away!
救护车，他们逃走了！
Stop them!
拦住他们！
We have located the subject and a witness who can confirm her identity.
我们已经找到了目标和一名可以确认其身份的目击者
She's exactly who we think she is.
她就是我们要找的那个人
We also have the position of her ship in orbit.
我们还掌握了她的飞船在轨道上的位置
Time to bring the baby home!
是时候带孩子回家了！
I love you guys!
我爱死你们了！
I've never felt so young in years!
好多年，我都没感觉这么年轻了！
The way you shook off those guys in traffic.
你甩掉那些人的方式
Brilliant!
太巴适了！
Yeah, the moment I ran the red lights,
是的，当我闯红灯时
sirens blaring, and then made that sudden left turn,
警笛大作，我突然左转
right in front of the oncoming truck and into the one-way street!
当着对向卡车的面，驶进了单行道！
It was like Star Wars, but with cars.
和星球大战一样，只不过我开的车
You know, Car Wars!
汽车大战！
I wish someone had filmed that.
我希望有人录下来了
I'm sure you're on at least
我觉得你至少
1325 traffic cameras.
被1325个监控摄像头拍到了
Let me just check if I can hack the server.
我来试试黑进他们服务器吧
Yeah, what a great chase.
是啊，速度与激情
There's nothing more exciting than expecting to die at any moment.
把脑袋别裤腰带上，真是爽死了
Four out of five stars.
你真是四星好市民
Why only four?
为啥才四星？
Because I survived.
因为老娘还活着！
Now I have to live with these memories for the rest of my life.
还得带着这份记忆活着！
Was it at least worth it?
不管咋说，这还是划算的
I was so sure Albio's record would lead us to something.
我以为能从阿尔比奥的记录看出些啥
But it's all really weird.
但这个太奇怪了
He was checked in in the evening with some kind of neurological disorder.
傍晚，他因某种神经失调被送进了医院
All kinds of tests were scheduled for the next day,
所有的检查都被安排在第二天
but he was declared missing the same night.
但当晚他就被宣布失踪了
No signs of third-party interference.
没有第三方干预的迹象
Looks like he just got up,
看起来他就是起床
walked out, and was never heard of again.
走出去，然后就人间蒸发了
So,
所以
seems like our little search is over.
看来我们的搜索到此为止了
Time to get off this shitty planet.
是时候离开这个粪坑了
You're already giving up?
你就这么放弃了？
After all what we've been through?
我们已经做了这么多了！
I thought that we're just getting warmed up.
我觉得我们刚刚热身完
Every minute we stay here gives our enemies more time to find us.
我们在这儿多待一分钟，敌人就多一分时间来找我们
Whoever that might be.
不管对面是谁吧
What I don't understand,
我还是不明白
I thought Albio was forced to leave Davida
你被家人胁迫回到地球之后
right after your family coerced you back to Earth.
阿尔比奥是被迫离开戴维达的
But no matter how I look at it,
但无论我怎么找
I can't find any evidence for that.
都找不到相关的证据
Of course you don't.
你当然找不到
They know exactly how to play this game.
他们对这个套路门清
What if he simply got cold feet once he realized what he'd gotten himself into?
如果他发现自己卷进这件事，就溜号了呢？
What did you just say?
你刚才说的啥子屁话？
Take that back or I will...
给我收回去！不然有你好果子吃！
What? Smash in my teeth?
干嘛？打掉我的牙齿吗？
Well, good luck lady, they're all stainless steel.
祝你好运，它们都是不锈钢的
I am fed up with this shit.
老娘受够这些屁事了
This whole thing was nothing but an elaborate trick.
这整件事就是个精心设计的圈套！
I've been researching Albio's whereabouts for years.
我追查阿尔比奥的下落很多年了
And then bam! Suddenly some documents appear
你猜咋的，突然就有文件冒出来了
and lure us right here to Earth.
还把我们勾引到了地球上
That's a bit far-fetched, don't you think?
这是不是有点太扯了？你觉得呢？
There are not too many people in this universe with access to a
在这个宇宙中，能接触到这么大的炸弹的人并不多
And among those are only two people who know about Albio.
这其中就两个人知道阿尔比奥的事
John and Meredith Stillwater.
约翰和梅雷迪斯·斯蒂尔沃特
That is not something parents do,
一般父母做不出来这种事
not even foster parents.
一般养父母也不会
You're paranoid.
你不要神戳戳的
I am not going to listen to you dribble any longer, old man.
老娘不想再听你瞎逼逼了，老登！
Sorin, let's go.
索林，我们走！
And let all this be for nothing?
所以我们白来了？
Oh no.
当然不是
You think I would be stupid enough to make this hell of
你以为我会傻到，为了那微乎其微的机会去找阿尔比奥
a trip for nothing but the unlikely chance to find Albio?
就冒这么大的险来这里吗
Then what else did you do it for?
你还做了什么？
Guess what?
猜猜看？
I brought Earth a little present.
我给地球送了个见面礼
What?
什么？
Sina, are you out of your mind?
西娜，你脑子里是不是有乒乓球？
That's insane!
这个离了大谱了！
Well,
好吧
did you believe I would just sit on top of
你以为我会就那么坐在炸弹上
the bomb and wait until the UN comes knocking?
等着联合国上门吗？
We're gonna blow it right up in their face in low orbit.
我们要直接在他们眼皮底下，在低轨道引爆
Over Stillwater Dynamics headquarters.
就在斯蒂尔沃特动力的总部上面
Nah.
这……
US...
联合国军方将会看到炸弹的型号
That will give the Stillwaters a lot of explaining
这会给斯蒂尔沃特带去不少麻烦
to do and hit them where it hurts the most.
专挑他们的死穴下手
The EMP will wipe out electronics in a radius of hundreds of kilometers.
电磁脉冲将摧毁方圆数百公里内的电子设备
Sina, you must be kidding me.
西娜，你是在扯淡吧！
I'm afraid she's not.
我觉得她不是
I just checked.
我检查了一下
The remaining container isn't pudding.
剩下的集装箱压根不是布丁
She knew we wouldn't have time for a full inventory check before departure,
她知道我们没有时间在出发前全面检查库存
so she swapped the cargo tags while we weren't looking.
于是她趁我们不注意，把货物标签换掉了
Sina,
西娜
you lied to me! You abused me!
你骗了我！还利用我！
Oh, really?
噢，是吗？
But didn't you dig up the story to get back to Earth in the first place?
可你当初挖掘这件事，不就是为了能回地球吗？
And here you are!
现在你不是回来了吗？
You've got exactly what you were promised.
你已经得到了承诺的东西
Plus a new identity and a sizable amount of starting capital.
再加上一个新身份和一笔可观的启动资金
You owe me a fucking space station, you know that?
你还欠了我一个他妈的空间站呢，你知道吗？
Blowing it up was your own free decision.
是你自己决定炸掉它的！
I even saved your life.
老娘还救了你的命呢
Which wouldn't have been in danger if these mercs hadn't been after your bloody ship,
如果那些雇佣兵没追你的该死的飞船，就不会有危险的
goddammit!
去你妈的！
Sina,
西娜
you're drunk and you're angry.
你已经醉得不行了
I'm not letting you bomb the planet in such a condition.
我不会允许你在这个情况下炸掉地球的
Then I will do it myself.
那老娘就请亲自动手
You're fired.
你被炒了
It's my ship now.
那是我的船！
And I'm still the commander.
但我还是指挥官！
I will let you know where you can pick it up when I don't need it anymore.
等我用完了，再告诉你在哪里取飞船
no, Sina!
不，西娜！
Sina, come back! Sit back down,
西娜，滚回来！给我老实坐着！
you're making a terrible mistake!
你要遭天谴！
Let me go!
放开老娘！
you motherfucker...
你他妈的……
Son of a bitch!
狗日的！
Hey, you! Ice Queen! That's enough! Come on!
喂，那边那个冰雪皇后！给我滚出去！
You come here!
跟我走！
Come on! Hey!
喂！快点！
Ice Queen comes with us!
我们把这个疯子抓住了！
Come on!
滚出去！
You can cool off outside!
要发疯去外面发去！
And I don't want to see your face ever again!
而且我再也不想看到你的脸了！
What the hell just happened?
刚才发生什么事了？
I don't know.
我不知道
Well,
好吧
looks like the Snow Queen flipped the lid.
看起来我们的冰雪皇后要翻天了
with a little luck she's so drunk she won't even make it to the spaceport.
希望她醉到她连太空港都到不了
She just called a shuttle.
她刚刚叫了个穿梭机
Damn.
完逑了
So how are we going to stop her now?
我们现在要怎么样才能阻止她？
Do you think it's really the UN who's after her?
你真的觉得是联合国在追杀她吗？
Or her parents?
或者她父母？
My best bet is on ERG.
我猜是ERG啊
They have a motive to blow up Juno.
他们有炸毁朱诺空间站的动机
They have the power to pull it off.
他们完全有能力做到
And they have a good reason to be after Sina.
而且有理由追杀西娜
They could have tracked us through Ten's tablet that was still logged into CommNet.
他们可以通过特伦特的平板电脑追踪到我们
Also,
对了
I have met the Stillwaters.
我见过斯蒂尔沃特夫妇
It's been a couple of years,
那是好多年以前了
but they were surprisingly down to earth for being as influential as they are.
他们很出名，但是非常低调
Agreed.
同意
From what we know,
从我们知道的来看
they actually cared a lot about her.
他们挺关心她的
Even when she got herself pregnant without a permit.
甚至当她无证怀孕时也是如此
I'm pretty sure they paramountly wanted to keep her from doing anything stupid.
我很确定，他们最重要的目的就是阻止她做傻事
And if she reacted back then when confronted
如果她当时在面对自己的错误时
with her own mistakes like she does today,
像今天这样反应的话
that would explain a lot.
这倒是解释清楚了
Say,
说起来
when was the last time she actually talked to her parents?
她上一次和父母说话是什么时候？
Well, I don't know.
我也不知道
A long time ago, I suspect.
我怀疑很久以前了
I don't remember her talking about them at all.
我都不记得她有提到过他们
She's on the shuttle now.
她上穿梭机了
Can you lock her out of the ship?
你能把她锁在飞船外面吗？
Not from here.
没法远程操作
Let's say goodbye to the world as we know it.
再见了，我们熟悉的世界
Deploying a bomb by hand from a container inside a cargo hold
你知道的，从货船的集装箱里手动
of a freighter is not exactly standard procedure, you know.
部署炸弹，可不是什么标准操作
At least, I don't think she'll be able to
至少，我觉得她醉成那样，是不可能成功的
So, we might still have some time.
所以，我们应该还有时间
Should we call the UN then?
我们要打电话给联合国吗？
That would literally be the end of the Pioneers.
那就是开拓者的末日了
If you want to save the world,
如果我们想拯救世界
we have to first save Sina from herself.
我们就必须先拯救西娜
Huh?
嗯哼？
What do you mean?
什么意思？
She's acting like a little girl who thinks there is a monster living
她的行为就像一个小女孩，认为床下藏着怪物
under her bed and that she can get rid of it by throwing a bomb on it.
而她以为扔颗炸弹就能把怪物消灭
A monster?
怪物？
That's her past catching up on her, right?
这就是她的过去，对吗
Precisely.
很准确
And there is only one way to destroy that monster.
只有一个办法能摧毁这个怪物
That sounds like you have a plan.
听起来你已经有计划了啊
I thought you'd never ask.
我还以为你不会问呢
Let's get dressed.
现在得穿正式点
We're going to meet some important people tonight.
我们今晚要去见一些大人物
Do you guys know how to play golf?
你们会玩高尔夫吗？
Public key accepted.
公钥通过
Two-factor authentication required.
需要双重验证
Please supply the passphrase.
请输入密码
How much wood would a woodchuck chuck if a woodchuck could chuck wood?
前轱辘不转后轱辘转，后轱辘不转前轱辘转
Thank you for calling Dynamo Trading Limited.
感谢呼叫Dynamo贸易有限公司
Please hold the line.
请保持连线
One day I'm going to string him for this passphrase.
总有一天，我会因为这个口令揍他一顿
Oh, hi Brian.
噢，你好啊，布莱恩！
What's up?
什么事？
Finally you're picking up.
你终于接电话了
I've been trying to reach you for hours!
我已经打了好几个小时了！
Don't forget to keep your back straight.
一定要保持背部挺直
Now,
现在
swing.
挥杆
And the next thing we're going to work on is your aim.
接下来我们要练习瞄准
Hang on, Brian's still on the phone.
稍等，布莱恩还在和我通话
BRIAN!
布莱恩！
Link, seriously?
林克，你在逗我吗？
Every fucking two or three letter agency in the solar system
全太阳系所有的特工都在追踪我们
is trying to get us and you're playing golf with your friends?
但你还在和朋友打高尔夫球？
Correction.
更正下
I'm playing golf with my friends and some very,
我在和朋友们，还有一些大人物打高尔夫
That's nice, but you do realize that the BI has just
很棒，你知道调查局刚刚在大街上贴了带你照片的通缉令吗？
Oh,
呃
are they still using that one from my old passport?
他们还在用我旧护照上的照片吗？
The one with the silly hair?
发型很搞笑那张？
No, this time they're using a more recent one.
不，他们用了张最新的
And it seems like you have a giant ice cream cone up your butt?
看起来你沟子里还夹了根巨大的甜筒
Oh, can you please get me a copy of that one?
笑死，你能帮我去拿一张吗？
I am totally going to frame that.
我要把那个裱起来挂我墙上
But how did they find out it's me?
但他们怎么知道那是我？
I should be invisible to their face recognition system.
他们的人脸识别系统应该看不到我
Well, you know, most living beings have some pretty good face recognition built in.
要知道，大多数生物都有很好的人脸识别功能
Someone recognized me?
有人认出我来了？
Who?
谁啊？
No idea,
不知道
but they updated your biometric profile and they know precisely where you are.
但他们更新了你的生物特征，并准确地知道你在哪里
Unless you manage to file and pay 15 years worth
除非你在接下来的五分钟内
of outstanding taxes within the next five minutes,
缴清过去15年的所有的税
you better get out of there.
不然你就快跑吧
You have a point.
你说得对
Is there a way we can stall these guys?
我们有办法拖住这些家伙吗？
I am not quite done here.
我这边的事还没办完
No?
没有？
Is it just the cameras or do they have any other way to track me?
只有摄像头，还是说他们有其他方法追踪我？
I have no idea.
我不清楚
I bet it's just the cameras.
我打赌只有摄像头
Link, you gotta run! Or rather drive! Now!
林克，你得跑了！或者说开车！就现在！
I know I'm taking a risk,
我知道我在冒险
but these people are worth it.
但和这些人是值得的
Trust me.
相信我
And besides, I'm also trying to save the world here.
再说了，我还在拯救世界
You've got some nerve!
你好不得了哦！
I don't need much time.
我不需要太长时间
Maybe an hour.
可能就一个小时
The camera system is extremely stupid.
摄像头系统非常愚蠢
You can fool it with a simple paper bag.
你用一个纸袋就能轻易骗过它
Yeah, I'm sure a crazy old guy on a golf cart wearing a paper bag
是啊，我敢肯定，一个开着高尔夫球车
over his face is not going to raise any suspicion whatsoever.
头上套着纸袋的疯老头绝对不会引起任何怀疑
Not if you create enough of a distraction.
只要你能制造足够多的干扰
Take the reward poster,
拿上通缉令
put it on all the message boards,
把它们贴上所有的留言板
and offer 5,000 Super Coins to anyone to print it out,
任何人，只要打印通缉令并贴在墙上
glue it to the nearest wall,
然后凭借和通缉令的自拍
and take a selfie.
就能获得5000超级金币
That will create a lot of false positives,
这会造成大量误报
filter that out should be just enough for me to finish the job.
应该正好够我把事情做完
5,000?
5000？
That's gonna cost you a fortune!
那得花你一大笔钱！
As I said, it will be worth it.
就像我说过的，这很值
Do it.
去做吧
Now.
现在就去
And I need you to organize a pickup for me.
我还需要你帮我安排一次接机
I gotta get off this planet and lay low for a while.
我得离开这个星球，低调一段时间
That's what you said last week,
你上周也是这么说的
and we all know where that went.
结果你看现在呢
No guts, no glory.
不入虎穴，焉得虎子
Link out!
林克下线！
I hate my life.
我真是受够了
That was close.
差一点
Oh Fuck!
卧槽了！
Ahh, I can't get this!
啊，我拿不起来
Ah, screw it.
去他的吧
yes, yes.
好了，好了
For Juno's sake.
看在朱诺的份子上
Good morning, Sina.
早上好，西娜
Oh, goodness, you look terrible.
哎哟，你脸怎么都垮起的
Yeah,
对啊
I'm hungover like a rocket.
我都喝麻了
What's up?
你有啥事？
I kinda don't want to stay behind on Earth,
我有点不想留在地球上
so will you let me dock?
你可以让我对接吗？
Sure.
当然
It's your ship, after all.
反正这是你的船
Where are you?
你在哪儿？
Here's my ID and vector.
这是我的身份证和数据
I'll be there in a minute.
我一分钟后就到
There you go.
我弄好了
Computer should guide you in.
计算机应该能引导你
Perfect.
完美
See you in a bit.
等会儿见
Sorin out.
索林下线
Shuttle docked to main chute.
穿梭机已与主舱道对接
Please confirm.
请确认
Yeah,
好
let them in.
让他们进来
Affirmative.
收到
Lyra!
莱拉！
What are you doing here?
你怎么来这里了？
Didn't you want to stay on Earth?
你不是想呆在地球上吗？
-I was worried about you! -Yeah, we all were.
我很担心你啊！
We came to help you.
我们是来帮你的
Then I hope you brought some hangover medication,
那我希望你们带了宿醉药
because this goddamn space truck doesn't seem to have any.
因为这辆该死的太空卡车好像没有
Do you remember what you did last night?
你还记得你昨晚干了什么吗？
Look,
停一下
if you came back to lecture me about morals,
如果你俩是过来教育我道德
world peace and everything I've done wrong in my life,
世界和平，以及我人生中犯下的每一个错误
you can fuck right off.
那你们就可以爬了
You're about to bomb the planet, Sina.
西娜，你差点把地球炸了！
Have you considered the possibility that things are not always what they seem?
你有没有想过，事情并不总是表面看起来的那样？
And why?
为啥？
Do you think I'm crazy?
你是不是觉得我脑壳有问题？
No,
不是
I think you're in pain.
我觉得你很痛苦
And I don't mean the hangover.
当然不是说你喝多了这个
You act like a cornered animal.
你就像被逼到墙角的狗一样
No rational thoughts and just fight or flight.
没有理智，只有战斗或逃跑
That's none of your business.
关你屁事
You're about to make this the business of 10 billion people!
你马上就要把这事变成一百亿人的事了！
Lyra, Lyra,
莱拉，莱拉
stop it, please.
请别说了
So,
所以
yeah,
对啊
there you have it.
就是这样
I'm hurting.
我很痛苦
I've been hurting for years.
多年来，我一直很痛苦
And the closer I get to
我越是接近这个该死的蓝色星球
the worse it got.
就越痛苦
But I'm going to make it stop once and for all.
但我要让它彻底停止
If you can't live with that,
如果你不能接受这一点
you better take a different ship home.
你最好换一艘飞船回家
But there is another way.
但还有另一种方法
While you were sleeping,
在你睡觉的时候
while you were sleeping off your little romp,
在你还不清醒的时候
Link helped me meet up with a few very interesting people back on Earth.
林克帮我在地球上认识了几个非常有趣的人
We talked a lot and
我们聊了很多
I learned a lot about you.
我学到了很多关于你的事情
I understand your pain now and your hate.
我现在理解你的痛苦和仇恨了
And I know what needs
而且我知道该怎么做
About me?
关于我的事？
Who on Earth would...
地球上有谁……
Oh no.
我草
You didn't.
不是吧
Tell me you didn't.
你不会真的……
Sina, calm down.
西娜，冷静下
Everything is all right.
一切都好得很
Computer,
电脑
how many passengers are on board of the shuttle?
穿梭机上有多少乘客？
There are two passengers on board of the shuttle.
穿梭机上有两名乘客
Computer,
电脑
close the airlock immediately.
立刻关闭气闸
Complying.
正在执行
Correction, unable to comply.
更正，无法执行
Door mechanism blocked.
闭锁装置失效
How dare you?
你是怎么敢的？
They just want to talk, okay?
他们只是想和你聊聊，好吗？
They really...
他们真的……
There is nothing to it.
和这个无关
They just want to talk.
他们只是想和你聊聊
You motherfucking son of a bitch betrayed me!
你个狗日的畜生！居然敢背叛老娘
No, no, no, Sina, stop it!
不，不，不，西娜，住手！
Soren!
索林！
Stay back or I will...
退后，不然我就……
Sina!
西娜！
What the hell are you doing here?
你们他妈的来这里干啥
It's so good to see you.
能见到你真好
We thought we'd never see you again.
我们以为再也见不到你了
You have ten seconds to get off my ship.
我数十下，从我船上滚下去
Ten?
十？
You're going to shoot an unarmed, defenseless man?
你要对一个手无寸铁的人开枪？
What happened to you?
你都经历过什么？
The daughter I knew would never have done that.
我认识的那个女儿绝不会那么做
How is life on Juno Station?
朱诺空间站的生活怎样？
Are you happy out there?
你在外面快乐吗？
I brought you some cake.
我给你带了些蛋糕
It even has real strawberries in it.
里面甚至还有真正的草莓
You always loved strawberries.
你一直很喜欢草莓
Here.
在这里了
Please,
拜托
take it.
拿着吧
It's for you.
这是给你的
Why are you doing this to me?
你们为什么要这样对我？
Why are you here?
你们为什么来这里？
Why?
为什么？
We've sent you so many messages over the last ten years,
在过去的十年里，我们给你发过很多信息
and you haven't answered a single one.
而你一直没有回复
What have we done to deserve this?
我们到底做了什么，才会变成这样？
You...
你们……
What have...
真是……
You know exactly and perfectly what you did!
你们心知肚明自己干了什么！
No, I don't.
不，我不知道
Bullshit!
胡说！
Sina,
西娜
can we sit down and talk?
我么能坐下来说吗？
Please,
求你了
just for a moment.
就一会儿
Okay,
行
fine.
好
If that means you'll leave me alone afterwards.
如果你们之后放过我的话
So be it.
那就这样吧
Now,
现在
Sina,
西娜
please tell us why you're so mad at us.
请告诉我们，你为什么这么生我们的气
Well,
行
who knows?
谁知道啊？
Maybe because you took away my unborn child.
或许是因为你们夺走了我未出世的孩子
Or maybe because you took away the man that I loved.
或许是因为你们夺走了我爱的人
Or, let me think,
或者，让我想想
maybe because you sent a motherfucking bomb to me.
也许是因为你们他妈给我寄了个炸弹
Is that really what you believe we did?
你真觉得是我们干的这事吗？
But why would we do that?
但是我们为什么要这样做啊？
Because I no longer fit your perfect little ideal of your perfect little poster child.
因为我已经不再是你心里那个完美小模范了
The daughter of leaders of the military-industrial complex,
军工复合体高层的女儿
running off with a dirty commoner during the steepest part of her career.
在事业最巅峰的时候，跟一个卑微平民私奔
I only ever had one perfect ideal,
我只有一个完美的想法
And that was making you happy!
就是让你感到开心！
Going to space was always your biggest dream.
进入太空一直是你最大的梦想
I made sure you got the best education,
我确保你接受最好的教育
so I helped you to enroll with the UN.
所以我帮你在联合国任职
Not because I wanted my own pet soldier.
不是因为我想要自己的贴身士兵
I did it to help you to make that dream come true,
我这样做是为了帮助你实现梦想
so you can be happy.
这样你就能开心了
I always thought that was obvious,
我一直认为这是显而易见的
but apparently it wasn't.
但现在看来不是
And for that,
为此
I truly blame myself every single day since you were gone.
自从你离开后，我每天都在自责
You are not mad at me for leaving the military?
我离开军队，你不生气吗？
Oh no.
当然不
Well, maybe we were for a while,
好吧，也许有段时间有点
but we learned to accept that you had to go your own way.
但我们也慢慢接受了，你得按自己的路走
And look what you achieved!
看看你取得了什么成就！
We are so proud of you.
我们为你感到骄傲
You can't imagine how many sleepless nights we spent
你无法想象我们度过了多少个不眠之夜
trying to find ways to keep you safe out there.
想方设法保证你在外面的安全
You're making this up.
你们这是编的吧
The UN has been under immense pressure by the extra
联合国一直受到ERG的巨大压力
We used all the power we have.
我们动用了所有的力量
We spent millions in campaigning money to keep that from happening.
我们花了数百万的资金运作来阻止这个
And now you're here to collect your reward?
现在你们来领赏了？
No, you are our daughter.
不，你是我们的女儿
We love you.
我们爱你
We want nothing in return.
不求回报
Not even your bomb?
那不是你们的炸弹吗？
Not even that.
那不是的
And it is not our bomb?
那不是我们的炸弹
Of course it is!
那个当然是！
It has your name on it!
上面有你们的名字！
That is a whole different story.
这完全是两码事
I'm not saying we didn't mess up,
我不是说我们没有搞砸
because we did in many ways.
因为我们用了很多方法
I got into the weapons business because I believed in the ideal of a united earth,
我进入武器行业，是因为我相信地球统一的理想
led by a democratic government,
由民主政府领导
able to put up a fight.
能真正抵抗威胁
Seeing the fight turning against you was one
看到战局对你不利，是我一生中最可怕的经历之一
And never have I felt so much regret.
我从未感到如此遗憾
But we did not send the bomb.
但炸弹不是我们送的
Neither did the UN military.
也不是联合国的军队
I swear.
我发誓
Then who did it?
那是谁做的呢？
Lyra gave us access to her research.
莱拉让我们查阅了她的研究
And everything points to ERG.
一切都指向了ERG
They have the resources,
他们有资源
the power and certainly a motive.
力量，以及动机
The device was definitely stolen.
设备肯定是偷来的
If you would hand it to us,
如果你能交给我们
we could look for evidence and bring the conspirators to court where they belong.
我们可以寻找证据，把阴谋者绳之以法，送上法庭
It would be your responsibility to decide that, of course.
当然，这事最终要你来做主
If that bomb explodes anywhere near planet Earth,
如果那颗炸弹在地球附近任何地方爆炸
it would be seen as the most sincere act of terrorism.
都会被视为恐怖主义行为
You know,
你知道的
technically the pioneers are still an illegal organization.
事实上，开拓者依然是非法组织
But a large part of earth's population secretly admires you, your spirit.
不过地球上很多人私下里都很佩服你，佩服你的勇气和精神
That would change overnight.
这一夜之间都会转变的
And our limited power to hold our shielding paws
我们那点勉强能护住朱诺空间站的力量
over Juno Station would be literally blown away.
根本撑不住，会被彻底摧毁
And always remember that whoever is going to be affected
永远记住，那些将会受到影响的人
also has a mother and a father and possibly a son or a daughter.
也都有父母，可能还有孩子
That's a pretty late realization for a weapons dealer, isn't it?
对一个武器商来说，这算是挺晚才意识到的吧？
Yes.
是啊
Too late, I know.
太晚了，我意识到了
Then I have one last question.
那么我还有最后一个问题
What happened to Albio?
阿尔比奥怎样了？
I seriously don't know.
我真的不知道
Be honest with me!
跟我说实话！
When you told us about your pregnancy,
当你告诉我们你怀孕的消息时
I had a long private conversation with him.
我和他进行了长时间的私下谈话
I asked him if he was aware of what he just did.
我问他，他有没有意识到自己刚刚做了什么
That both of you would have to face severe consequences if you carried out that child.
如果你真的生下孩子，你们俩都得承担严重后果
And if he was ready to give up his current life for you,
我问他是否准备为你放弃现在的生活
lose his job, face the fines.
失去工作，承担罚款
I tried to appeal to his reason and his conscience.
我试图唤起他的理智和良知
It seemed like he hadn't spent a single thought on the future.
可显然他根本没考虑过未来
He eventually panicked and hung up on me.
他最后慌了，直接挂了电话
That is the last time I ever heard from him.
从那以后，我再也没有他的消息
No way!
不可能！
It looks like he took what he still had and ran away.
看来他带着自己剩下的东西就跑了
And if he hadn't abandoned you that day,
如果那天他没有离开你
he would have done so later.
那他迟早会的
If that's really the truth,
如果这是真的
then why did you never tell me?
那你们为什么从来不告诉我？
Why?
为什么？
I tried literally hundreds of times,
我试了上百次
but you wouldn't listen.
但你不听
I'm such a ruthless piece of shit.
我简直不是个东西
No,
不
you are not.
你不是
And this is not my proudest day either.
这一天也算不上我光彩的一天
But we are still family.
我们是一家人
Together we can pull through this.
我们要一起渡过难关
I really wish we could.
我希望我们能
I don't see why we couldn't.
我不明白为什么我们不能
You don't understand.
你们不懂的
Understand what?
不懂什么？
We can't go back.
我们不能回去了
The bomb is already in orbit.
炸弹已经部署到轨道上了
Are you kidding me?
你他妈在逗我？
Kamari, if you don't calm down,
卡玛丽，如果你不冷静下来
I'm going to call security.
我就得叫保安了
Almost a month of research,
差不多一个月的调研
interviews, inquiries, filming, editing,
采访，询问，拍摄，剪辑
all for what?
到头来是为了什么？
Nothing?
什么都没有？
But Kamari, that's part of our job.
卡玛丽，这就是我们工作的部分内容
This isn't just some filler material.
这可不是随便的素材
This is stuff people have a right to know about.
而是人们有权知道的事情
I know that you put a lot of work into your report.
我知道你在报道上投入了很多心血
And rejecting it wasn't easy.
拒绝它也不是件容易的事
But we discussed it with the National Broadcasting Council.
但我们和国家广播委员会讨论过
And we came to the conclusion that
得出的结论是
it would be irresponsible to show a report like that right now.
现在播出这样的报道不负责任
It's irresponsible not to show it.
但不播也同样不负责任
Right now we have violent protests in front of ERG's headquarters.
现在ERG总部前正在发生暴力抗议
Half of the African continent is still rejecting the
半个非洲大陆仍拒绝联合国世界政府
UN World Government and they are arming themselves up.
并在武装自己
The Socialist Party is calling for an impeachment of the president.
社会党正在呼吁弹劾总统
The BI and the Federal Police have just suspended a quarter
调查局和联邦警察因贿赂指控
of their executive staff for allegations of bribery.
停职了四分之一的高管
And you say throwing a bomb like that into an already
你却说，在这种不稳定局势下扔一颗炸弹才是负责任的做法？
A free press is the foundation of democracy.
自由媒体是民主的基石
We can't hold back the truth just because it might upset someone.
我们不能因为可能冒犯某些人就隐瞒真相
If you look at the scale of everything that is happening right now,
看看现在发生的一切
people aren't nearly as upset as they should be.
人们的反应远没有他们应该有的强烈
You got some great points,
你说得有道理
but it's all very incomplete and inconclusive.
但报道内容非常不完整，也无法下定论
Of course it's incomplete.
当然不完整
That's because it's a developing story that is happening right now.
那是因为事情还在发展
And so far, we're the only ones who know about it.
而目前只有我们知道
Wait until the rest of the world gets their hands on this.
等全世界都知道这件事，会更震惊
But what if you're wrong?
但如果你错了呢
Wrong about what?
什么错了？
That something is going on?
说是有事情发生？
Hell, did you even read the goddamn script?
天啊，你到底读没读报告啊？
Within just a few weeks,
几周内
an ERG freighter goes missing in the middle of nowhere,
ERG货船凭空失踪
Link Kabanshee Station gets destroyed by a nuclear explosion in plain sight,
林克·卡班西的空间站被核爆摧毁
and some impostors trying to steal patient records related to Sina Stillwater
一些冒充者试图窃取西娜·斯蒂尔沃特相关的病历
get chased through the city of Stockholm in an ambulance.
还在斯德哥尔摩的街头开着救护车逃亡
And everyone is acting like it all never happened.
而大家却装作什么都没发生
It's almost like someone powerful is doing all they can to cover something up.
简直就像有人在竭力掩盖真相
Weird stuff happens all the time.
奇怪的事情每天都发生
These things could be completely unrelated.
这些可能完全无关
Then you might be interested in the documents I got this morning.
那你可能会对我今天早上拿到的文件感兴趣
Here, look at them.
看看这些
Oh,
我到底该看什么？
That's the passenger list of the Darwin,
这是达尔文号货船的乘客名单
the freighter that disappeared in sector
达尔文号货船在4385区失踪
Look at line 31.
看第31行
Lyra Senick?
莱拉·西尼克
Who is she again?
她是谁来着？
She's a good friend of mine and one of my most reliable sources.
她是我一个好朋友，也是我最可靠的消息来源
She was the one who blew the cover of the
正是她揭露了调查局和ERG勾结的内幕
She should have won a Pulitzer for that,
她本该赢得普利策奖
but the powers that be sent her to Vesta instead.
但当权者把她押去维斯塔
But she never arrived there.
可她从未抵达那里
Swipe left.
再往左翻
Here is the security camera footage from the
这是斯德哥尔摩卡罗琳斯卡大学医院的监控录像
It shows the alleged impostors.
显示所谓的冒充者
Stop here.
停
Now zoom in.
放大看
There.
这里
Who are they?
他们是谁
Lyra Senick,
莱拉·西尼克
Sina Stillwater,
西娜·斯蒂尔沃特
and Link Kabanshee.
还有林克·卡班西
Alive,
活着
free, and on this very planet.
自由，而且就在地球上
Bam!
靠！
Still think the events aren't related?
你还认为这些事件无关吗？
That can't be.
不可能
Their faces would have been flagged by every security camera the moment
按理来说，他们一踏上地球就会被监控识别
And yet here they are.
但他们还在这里
But it gets better.
更精彩的是
Swipe left once more.
再往左翻
And what's that?
这又是什么？
A document leaked by a whistleblower about an internal UN military investigation.
是一份举报者泄露的联合国内部军事调查文件
Apparently a bomb went missing.
显然有一颗炸弹失踪
And not just any bomb.
而且不是普通炸弹
A Stillwater Dynamics D-Z/4 antimatter bomb.
而是斯蒂尔沃特动力的SD-Z/4反物质炸弹
Kamari, do you have any idea what happens if
卡玛丽，你知道如果这些信息落入错误的人手里会怎样吗？
What do you mean, the wrong hands?
什么意思，错误的人？
I'm going to ask you to seize your investigation immediately.
我要求你立即停止调查
I'm transferring you to the Department of Regional Affairs.
我要把你调到区域事务部
-The hell you are! -Regional Affairs, Kamari,
去你的吧！
effective immediately.
立刻生效
Clarence,
克拉伦斯
this is bullshit! I quit!
这简直是胡闹！我辞职！
That's your choice.
那是你的选择
Just don't forget you're still bound by the non-disclosure agreement you signed.
但别忘了，你仍然受签署的保密协议约束
Unless you want to end up like your friend Lyra.
除非你想像你朋友莱拉那样
Did you just threaten me?
你这是在威胁我？
Yes, I absolutely did.
是的，我就是在威胁你
You'd better be careful who you mess with.
最好小心点，别惹错人
Oh, it was you who blew Lyra's cover, right?
哦，是你揭露莱拉的身份的吧？
How dare you!
你是怎么敢的！
The protection of our sources is the key to a free press.
保护消息来源是自由媒体的义务
A free press?
自由媒体？
There is no such thing.
不存在的
Never was.
从来都不存在
And speaking of freedom,
说到自由
you're now free to go.
你现在可以自由离开了
And you'd better do so quickly before I change my mind.
而且最好快走，别让我改变主意
Farewell, Ms. Suarez.
再见，苏亚雷斯女士
We wish you a lot of success for your future career path.
祝你未来职业顺利
And don't forget,
也别忘了
we'll be watching you.
我们会关注你的
Farewell, Mr. Blankenship.
再见，布兰肯希普先生
And fuck you!
去你妈的！
Okay,
好了
we're at a safe distance now.
我们在安全距离上了
You're still sure you want to do this alone?
你确定你要一个人上吗？
I fucked it up.
我捅破的天
I'm going to fix it.
我自己补上
Approaching the container now.
正在接近集装箱
Alright, let me know when it's safe to approach again.
好吧，到安全的时候再告诉我，我再靠近
I wasn't planning to set up camp.
我没打算待太久
And touchdown.
我摸到了
I'm going to open the hatch now.
我要打开箱子了
careful out there!
小心点
Oh,
噢
yeah, yeah, I got it, I got it.
我知道，我知道
Everything is under control.
一切都在掌控之中
There we go.
现在我们开始吧
Hurry up! There's a small vehicle on the radar and it's approaching fast.
快点！雷达上有一辆小型载具，正快速接近
It seems we're not the only ones looking for this thing.
看来不止我们在找这东西
I'll do my best.
我尽力吧
They're getting closer.
他们越来越近了
Shit!
操！
What is it?
发生什么了？
It won't scan my paw through the spacesuit.
它不能隔着宇航服扫描我的爪子
Well, Meredith said it should.
梅雷迪思说应该可以的
But it doesn't.
但它没有
Okay, keep trying.
好吧，继续尝试
Fuck, fuck, fuck, fuck.
搞啥子哦！
Why doesn't it work?
咋个就不行嘛！
I've got a visual on the other ship now.
我现在看到另一艘船了
It is a tiny vessel.
是一架小型穿梭机
It seems like some sort of mining drone.
好像是某种采矿无人机
Seems like ERG wants to get their toy back.
看来ERG想要拿回他们的玩具
Okay, we're coming.
行了，我们来了
No!
不要！
If this thing goes off,
这东西一炸
the radiation is going to grill you.
你就会被辐射烤熟
I don't care.
我不管了
We're coming back.
我们回来了
No!
不行！
Shut up!
闭嘴！
You're supposed to keep my parents out of the goddamn blast zone.
你应该让我爸妈远离他妈的爆炸区
Which part of shut up do I have to explain to you?
闭嘴，我得再给你解释一遍吗？
Your mom and dad are fine.
放心吧，你爸妈没事
Both just gave me the thumbs up.
他们刚刚都比了大拇指
Can you get rid of that ERG ship?
你能摧毁那艘ERG的飞船吗？
Not really.
不行
We're in Earth orbit.
我们在地球轨道上
The moment we draw anyone's attention,
一旦我们吸引到某人的注意力了
we have a problem.
我们就有大麻烦了
Oh, fuck.
去他妈的
Okay, we're close enough.
好了，我们很接近了
I'm going to send Lyra over with a tether now.
我现在就用缆绳把莱拉送过去
This is going to be extremely fiddly.
这将会非常麻烦
This ship isn't equipped to pick up objects in space,
这艘船没配备在太空中拾取物体的设备
so what we're going to do is line up as good as we can
所以我们要做的是尽量对准
and then slowly pull the container in with a steel cable.
然后用钢索慢慢把集装箱拉进来
And pray it doesn't do too much damage when it crashes into the cargo holds.
希望它撞进货舱时不要造成太大损伤
But if we don't get it disarmed first,
不过如果我们不先把它停掉
that will be the least thing to worry about.
那简直连最小的问题都算不上
Careful, Sina.
小心，西娜
I'm coming in now.
我来了
Oh,
噢
this is a lot harder than it looks.
这比我想象的难多了
I have no idea how you always make this look so effortless.
我不知道你们是怎么做到的，总能轻松得一匹
So,
所以
making any progress down there?
有进展吗？
Not really.
没有
Keep trying.
继续试
Sorin wants me to weld the hook to one of the support beams so he can attach a tether.
索林要我把钩子焊接到其中一根支撑梁上
Have you ever used a welder in space?
你在太空中使用过焊机吗？
Uh, nope.
呃，没有
Oh, shit.
完蛋了
Okay,
行吧
hold on then.
抓紧了
I will do it.
我来焊接吧
Uh, my ladies, I'm afraid we're getting company.
女士们，恐怕有人来了
What the fuck are they trying to accomplish?
他们到底想干嘛？
Uh, there's someone coming from the other ship, even.
有人从另一艘船上过来了
Quick, grab the tether and I'll pull you both back in.
快，抓住缆绳，我把你们俩拉回来
I'm not going anywhere.
我哪里都不去
If they want their bomb back,
如果他们想要拿回炸弹
they'll have to take it from my cold,
那就得从我的尸体上踏过去
No,
不要啊
Lyra! Lyra, get back over here! That thing is hydraulic.
莱拉！莱拉，快回来！那东西是液压的
It's a million times stronger than you.
它的力量是你的一百万倍
Lyra,
莱拉，他有枪！
We need to get out of here.
我们得赶紧撤退
Oh, shit!
完蛋了！
This will be our last chance to bail out.
这是我们最后一次撤离机会
Give me the end of the tether.
快把缆绳给我！
No,
不
wait.
等下
Take it.
拿着
But I'm not going with you.
但我不会跟你走
What?
什么？
I have an idea.
我有个想法
What the fuck are you doing?
你他妈要干嘛？
You know what, Sina?
你知道吗，西娜？
You were right.
你是对的
When I began snooping on you and your history with Albio and your parents,
当我开始窥探你
I didn't really care about you.
我不关心你
But things have changed.
但一切都变了
I do care now.
现在我关心了
I owe you this.
这是我欠你的
Here.
这里
Hold the welder and take care of the tether,
握住焊机，小心系绳
okay?
好吗
You don't have to do this.
你没必要这样做
But I want to.
但我想做
Shit!
妈的！
I think I cracked the rib.
我的排骨好像断了
You better get this thing installed before it comes back.
你最好在它回来之前把它装好
Yeah, I've tried everything.
我什么都尝试过了
It refuses to scan my paw.
它不扫描我的爪子
How drunk were you when you set it up?
你在安装时到底喝得有多麻啊？
I don't even remember doing it.
我都不记得我做过这个
Have you tried the other paw?
你试过另一只爪子嘛？
What?
什么？
-The other paw! -Why should I scan my other paw?
另一只爪子！
Just do it!
做就完了！
Okay.
行吧
Sina?
西娜？
Did you do it?
你做了吗？
Yes, it's safe.
好了，现在安全了！
Let's get out of here.
赶紧撤退吧
All right.
好的
Lyra!
莱拉！
It's crushing me!
我快被压碎了！
Lyra! Lyra!
莱拉！莱拉！
Hold on!
坚持住！
What the fuck is going on down here?
下面到底发生什么事了？
Come on!
快点！
Let her go, you stupid thing!
放开她，你这个破烂玩意儿！
There we go.
好了
Lyra!
莱拉！
Lyra, can you hear me?
莱拉，能听见我说话吗！
Sorin! Lyra is hurt! Call emergency services!
索林，莱拉受伤了，快呼叫急救
We'll be ready to come back to the ship in a minute!
我们马上就可以回到船上了！
All right!
好的
Let me know when.
到时候告诉我
Not so fast, Sina!
慢点，西娜
Lyra! Are you okay?
莱拉！你还好吗？
Everything hurts, but I think I'll live.
到处都痛，但我还撑得住
I never thought I would be so glad to hear your voice.
我从未觉得你的声音如此动听
Hang in there.
抓稳了
We're going back.
我们回去吧
You thought I'd miss the chance to ride the bomb back home?
你以为我会错过搭炸弹回家的机会吗？
No way!
不可能的！
You are so much braver than I will ever be.
你比我任何时候都要勇敢得多
All right.
好了
Here we go.
我们回去吧
There.
焊好了
That will do the job.
这个应该能行
Sorin, we're ready to go.
索林，我们准备好了！
Pull us in, but gently.
拉我们一把，但要轻
Well then,
那好吧
here goes nothing.
真是松了口气
one, go!
1，开始！
Breaking news!
突发新闻！
Convicted former freelance journalist survives the
被判有罪的前自由记者
hijacking of her prisoner transport vessel by a terrorist,
在被恐怖分子劫持的运输船上幸存下来
and not only saves the Pioneers from having
不仅救了开拓者们
Juno Station destroyed by an antimatter bomb,
避免朱诺空间站被反物质炸弹毁掉
but also delivers it safely back to its rightful owners,
还将炸弹安全送回了它的合法拥有者
while uncovering a system-wide conspiracy between the various
同时，她揭露了联合国各机构
UN agencies and the system's largest mining corporation, ERG.
与系统最大采矿公司ERG之间的阴谋
And if you think that headline was quite a mouthful, you're absolutely right.
如果你觉得这个标题有点长
Our colleague, Frayden Schultz, who has just returned
那你说得没错。我们的同事弗雷登·舒尔茨
from the press conference at the President's office,
刚从总统办公室的新闻发布会回来
will hopefully be able to break it down for us.
将为我们详细解读
Yes, Simon, I think it is safe to say that this is the
是的，西蒙，可以说这是有史以来
biggest scandal that has ever rocked the solar system.
震惊整个太阳系的最大丑闻
We all remember the Supreme Court's landmark decision that the independent settlement
我们都记得最高法院的里程碑式判决
on Juno does not fall under Earth jurisdiction,
朱诺空间站上的定居点不受地球管辖
and fundamental human rights prohibited UN military
并且基本人权禁止联合国军事干预
to intervene unless there are signs of an actual threat to the UN.
除非存在对联合国的实际威胁
Today,
今天
mounting evidence was revealed that ERG officials,
有越来越多的证据显示
who had strongly pushed towards a military intervention against the Pioneers,
强烈推动对开拓者进行军事干预的ERG官员
tried to take the situation into their own hands.
试图自行掌控局势
Apparently,
显然，他们协助恐怖分子
antimatter bomb and sent him to destroy Juno.
非法获取反物质炸弹，并派其去摧毁朱诺空间站
That almost sounds like the plan of a cartoon super villain.
这听起来简直像动画片里的超级反派计划
Absolutely,
完全正确
and the amount of collusion necessary to make this happen is staggering.
要实现这一切所需的勾结程度令人震惊
But all it took to topple this house of cards was one single eyewitness.
但推倒这个纸牌屋只需要一位目击者
Her testimony has already been recorded two weeks ago,
她的证词两周前就已记录
but the investigation has been
但调查一直保密
kept secret until this morning,
直到今天早晨
the UN Guard conducted a simultaneous concerted crackdown
联合国警卫同时对ERG
on various ERG and government offices.
和政府的多个办公室展开集中打击
Many officials,
许多官员
including ERG's fleet officer Theodor Copland and BI chief Henry Lewis,
包括ERG舰队官员西奥多·科普兰和调查局局长亨利·路易斯
are now facing charges of corruption,
现在面临贪腐
25 cases of murder,
25起谋杀案
more than 500 cases of attempted murder,
500多起未遂谋杀案
illegal weapons trade, terrorism,
非法武器交易、恐怖主义
treason and many more.
叛国等多项罪名指控
Did the president give us any perspective
总统是否给出过
on what the consequences might be within the government?
政府内部可能产生的影响？
UN President Garza said he is shocked and
联合国总统加尔扎表示
appalled by the recent events and that parliament
他对近期事件感到震惊和愤慨
is already in session to determine which
议会已开会讨论
reforms need to be enacted in order to prevent
需要实施哪些改革
something like this to happen again.
以防止类似事件再次发生
This will also definitely have a huge impact on
这也将对针对ERG的反垄断程序产生巨大影响
Now tell me a bit about the eyewitness,
再来说说这位目击者
who is she and how did she get involved?
她是谁，又是如何卷入的？
This is another story straight out of Hollywood.
这是另一段好莱坞式的故事
Her name is Lyra Senick,
她的名字是莱拉·西尼克
a journalist from Boston Massachusetts,
来自马萨诸塞州波士顿的记者
sentenced to forced labor on Vesta for trying to uncover part
因为试图揭露这场阴谋的一部分，被判到维斯塔服劳役
She miraculously survived the hijacking of the ERG ship
她奇迹般地幸存于劫持
managed to overwhelm the hijacker and took the ship to Juno station to get help.
成功制服劫持者，将船开到朱诺空间站寻求帮助
What happened after that is still classified information,
之后发生的事情仍属于机密
but if a full story is ever going to be released,
但如果完整故事公布
it'll be one for the history books for sure.
必将载入史册
Thanks a lot Brayden Schultz,
谢谢你，弗雷登·舒尔茨
we'll continue to check in with you as the story develops.
我们将随着事态发展继续关注你的报道
You're welcome.
谢谢
Now back to Inside Politics.
现在，回到《政治内幕》节目
Telling the truth to those in power should neither
向掌权者说出真相
But it still is.
但现实却是如此
When I dared to tell the truth,
当我敢于说出真相时
I was framed and shipped to Vesta for a crime I did not commit.
我被陷害，为一桩我未犯的罪行被送往维斯塔
But I think if more of us chose to speak the truth,
但我认为，如果我们中有更多人选择说出真相
we would be in a better place right now.
现在的情况会好得多
So it is our job, our obligation,
所以，向权力说出真相，是我们的工作
our duty to speak truth to power.
是我们的责任，是我们的义务
Not just when it's difficult,
不是只在容易的时候说
but especially when it's difficult.
而是尤其在困难的时候说
Thank you.
谢谢大家
If you want to know more,
如果你们想要了解更多
please buy my book "JUNO RISING" and learn how the former ERG
请购买我的书《朱诺崛起》，了解前ERG集团
tried to go to war against those who dared to think different.
如何试图对敢于发声的人发动战争
If you already have a copy,
如果你已经有了书
you can get it signed at the terminal by the stage.
可以到舞台旁的展台签名
Oh, uh, hey Lyra.
你好啊，莱拉
I'd love to talk to you in real time,
我很想和你实时交流
but you know, the speed of light is against us.
但你也知道，光速是有限的
I hope your TAD talk went well.
我希望你的TAD演讲顺利
I bet you were nervous as hell,
我打赌你一定紧张得要命
but I'm sure you absolutely nailed it as always.
但我相信，你绝对会和之前一样，做得完美
I'm sorry I can't be there in person,
很抱歉，我不能亲临现场
but as you can imagine,
但和你想的一样
I'm needed here more than ever.
这里比以往任何时候都需要我
It's Sally's first day back at home and we're still
今天是萨莉回家的第一天
getting used to having a little cub in the house again.
我们还在适应家里又有一只小宝宝的生活
Hey sweetheart,
喂，亲爱的
can you come over for a second?
你能过来一下吗？
I'm recording a message for Lyra.
我在给莱拉录一段视频
Lyra,
莱拉
meet Maya.
这是玛雅
Isn't she beautiful?
她真漂亮啊！
She's all I ever dreamed of, and without you,
她就是我梦寐以求的孩子
she would never have seen the light of day.
没有你，她根本不会来到这个世界
And for that,
为此
we will forever thank you.
我们永远感激你
I hope you can overcome your fear of space again and be able to come over for a visit.
希望你能重新克服对太空的恐惧，过来看看她
We miss you.
我们想你
Take care.
保重
Sorin,
索林
out.
下线
She's so cute.
她真可爱啊！
Dear TAD attendees,
亲爱的TAD观众们
we would like to announce that the buffet is now open in the planetary ballroom.
现在通知大家，行星舞厅已经开始提供自助餐
Hello.
有人吗
Where is everybody?
人们都去哪里啦？
Oh well.
哎，好吧
Why should Lyra Senick,
为什么《纽约时报》畅销书作者莱拉·西尼克
care for an old man like me?
会在乎像我这样的老人呢？
She's a celebrity now after all.
人家现在是大人物了
Who gives a damn about old friends?
哪个还管老朋友哦
Lyra?
莱拉？
You're standing on my tail!
你踩我尾巴上了！
Oh, I'm sorry.
对不起
I'm sorry.
实在不好意思
Apparently,
显然，自动驾驶仪认为你是家具的一部分
You're the last one I expected to show up here.
我真没想到你会出现在这里
So, how have you been?
你最近怎么样？
Or rather,
或者说
where have you been?
你去哪儿了？
I thought you were gone for good.
我还以为你一去不回了
I'm sorry I had to leave so suddenly,
对不起，我不得不突然离开
but nuking my station got me a lot of unwanted attention.
核爆空间站的行为，给我招来了很多不必要的关注
I had to go underground for a while to fix my
我不得不暂时潜伏起来，整顿生意
business and make sure I lived to tell the tale.
并确保自己能活着把故事讲出来
But I'm glad I still managed to hook you up with the Stillwaters.
但我很高兴，还是让你们和斯蒂尔沃特夫妇联系上了
Life wouldn't have been the same if the bomb went off.
如果炸弹爆炸了，生活就完全不一样了
I never got to thank you for that.
我还没来得及感谢你呢
Is there anybody you don't know?
还有你不知道的人吗？
It's just a rhetorical question.
开个玩笑罢了
So, how did you like my talk?
我的演讲怎么样？
Oh,
我很喜欢！我还买了了一本你的书
I hope it has pictures of Sina's face when her parents showed up.
真希望这里面有西娜看到她爸妈出现时的表情
I'm afraid not.
肯定没有的
But if you come over to the terminal,
如果你来展台
I can even put in a dedication for you.
我还能给你写个专属题词
No, thank you.
谢谢不用了
But if I wanted a digital signature,
如果我想要电子签名
I could just forge one myself.
我完全能自己做一个
Can I have an old-fashioned one instead?
能给我来一个老式的吗？
One with a pen?
用笔吗？
On an e-book?
在电子书上？
How's that supposed to work?
这怎么做的到？
No, not on an e-book, silly.
傻瓜，当然不是在电子书上
Here,
这里
I printed it all out.
我把整本都打印出来了
Oh,
哦，好吧
To Link Kabanshee, my old friend.
致老朋友，林克·卡班西
Sorry for the station.
对不起，毁了你的空间站
I'll buy you a new one as soon as I can.
我会尽快给你买一个新的
Yours,
你的，莱拉
Wonderful,
完美，谢谢
So, have you set up a new shop yet?
那么，您新店铺开张了吗？
Yes and no.
是，也不是
I have managed to score an old CommNet relay in the belt.
我设法在小行星带弄到了一个老旧的CommNet中继站
And we are building the first off-world data center.
我们正在建立第一个外星数据中心
EMP-hardened, tax-free,
抗电磁脉冲，免税，隐私保护
And what did you call it?
你给它取了名字没？
The Pirate Bay?
海盗湾吗？（这个是真实存在的盗版资源网站）
I like the ring of that.
这个听起来不错
Lyra!
莱拉！
Sina!
西娜！
-Link! -John!
林克！
-Meredith! -Lyra! -Link!
梅雷迪斯！
-Sina! -John! -Lyra!
西娜！
-Link! -Meredith!
林克！
Janet!
珍妮特！
-Dr. Scott! -Brad! -Rocky!
斯科特博士！
Sorry for letting you guys wait,
抱歉让你们久等了
but I just ran into this old guy here.
我刚刚撞到这个老家伙了
Or rather,
或者说
he ran into me.
他撞到我了
Okay, then let's go eat.
好了，我们去吃饭吧！
The buffet has some real veggies and meat.
自助餐有一些真正的蔬菜和肉类
You don't get much good food on Juno,
在朱诺空间站，你吃不到什么好东西吧？
I think there is still some chocolate pudding left.
我觉得应该还剩了点巧克力布丁
But seriously,
不过说真的
the food situation has improved so much since we don't have to smuggle it anymore.
现在不用再走私食物了，餐饮情况好了太多
The Pioneers have never had a better relationship with Earth.
开拓者与地球的关系从未如此好
We have an embassy now.
我们现在有大使馆了
We can legally trade.
我们能合法贸易
We have our own CommNet domain.
我们有自己的CommNet域名
And all thanks to the political fallout of the ERG scandal.
这一切都要归功于ERG丑闻带来的政治余波
Whoever came up with the idea to attack us got the exact opposite of what they wanted.
他们想攻击我们，结果完全适得其反
Karma is a bitch.
人作有祸，天作有雨
Hell yeah.
确实
And it even gets better.
还有更好的
Juno Station is going to be 100% legal by the end of the month.
朱诺空间站将在本月底完全合法化
And that clears the last barrier of our acceptance as a sovereign nation.
这也清除了我们作为主权国家被承认的最后障碍
Wow! How did that happen?
哇！怎么做到的！
I will let you in on a secret.
我告诉你一个小秘密
You know, the UN decided to break up the ERG monopoly, right?
你知道联合国决定拆分ERG垄断对吧？
A little bird sang to me which of the new companies
有风声告诉我，新成立的公司里，哪一家将合法拥有朱诺
And another little birdie sang to me that the stocks will be dirt cheap.
还有消息说，股票便宜到爆
What?
难以置信！
You actually bought Juno?
你把朱诺空间站买下来了？
A lot more than just Juno, but
不仅仅是朱诺空间站，还有……
the deal is still in progress.
交易还在进行中
Hey! No insider trading!
喂！别搞内幕交易！
What?
啥啊？
I was just checking my email.
我只是在看我的邮件
That's so awesome!
太棒了！
I'm so happy for you!
我真为你感到高兴！
Where did all the money suddenly come from?
这些钱到底是从哪儿突然冒出来的？
I sold all my stocks in Stillwater Dynamics and set up a fund.
我把在斯蒂尔沃特动力公司的所有股票都卖掉了
It wasn't an easy decision,
这并不是一个容易的决定
but the bomb incident was quite a rude awakening.
但那次炸弹事件让我彻底清醒了一回
I think in the end,
我想最终
the Pioneers will help our freedom more than weapons ever could.
开拓者们比任何武器，更能帮助我们自由
Yeah.
就是这样的
And so,
那么
are we going for lunch or not?
这午饭还吃不吃了？
I'm starving!
我肚子都闹革命了！
Sure, let's go.
当然，我们走吧
Okay.
好啊
Earth food, here I come!
地球美食，我来了！
I would never have imagined ever hear you say that.
我从来没想过会听你说出这句话
What the hell?
什么毛病？
Oh, for fuck's sake, not now!
搞啥子！就不能等会儿吗？
I'll be with you in a minute.
我马上就来！
Brian!
布莱恩！
The bloody chair ain't working!
这破椅子坏逑了！
Brian?
布莱恩？
Have you tried turning it off and on again?
你试过关机重启吗？
Of course I did!
我当然试过了！
Maybe the stem bolt didn't steer properly?
也许是螺丝没有拧紧？
And what can I do about that?
那我又能咋办呢？
Eh, nothing?
呃，啥也干不了？
Oh, come on, you piece of junk!
这破玩意儿咋这么不争气！
Eh,
呃，林克！千万别这么做！这是个轮椅！
not a tank! Link! No!
不是坦克！林克！不！
Oh, who gives a shit about experts' opinion nowadays?
哎哟，这年头专家的话也不好使了！
Good luck!
祝你好运吧！
Finally!
终于！
Standby for ignition in five,
准备点火，5
♪ As  I  see  the  Juno  rise ♪
当我看到朱诺升起
♪ Into  my  orbit ♪
进入我的轨道
♪ I  think  of  all  the  tired  eyes ♪
我念及所有疲惫的眼眸
♪ And  know, ♪
而后知晓
♪ I  already  chose  a  side ♪
我早已选定心之所向
♪ It  might  be  the  greatest  gift ♪
这或许是最珍贵的馈赠
♪ Providing  us  a  hiding  place ♪
为我们筑起一处栖身之境
♪ It  let  me  be  alone. ♪
让我得以独享这份寂静
♪ As  if  there  was  a  going  back ♪
仿佛真能回溯往昔那般
♪ Nothing  left  behind  can  pull  me  there ♪
但身后再无事物能将我牵绊
♪ What  was  has  been  erased ♪
过往早已被抹去
♪ Yet  we’re still fighting ♪
可我们仍在奋力抗争
♪ You  can’t  blame  me  for  trying ♪
你怎能怪我竭力一试
♪ I’m  gonna  live  while  dying ♪
我要在消逝中寻得生机
♪ Planets  still  reflect  the  light ♪
行星虽无法自放光芒
♪ though  they  don’t  produce  their own. ♪
却依旧折射着璀璨微光
♪ We  still  see  them  spinning  off ♪
我们仍能看见它们旋转不息
♪ and  always  moving. ♪
永不停歇，奔赴远方
♪ It  might  be  the  greatest  gift ♪
这或许是最珍贵的馈赠
♪ Providing  us  a  hiding  place ♪
为我们筑起一处栖身之境
♪ It  let  me  be  alone. ♪
让我得以独享这份寂静
♪ As  if  there  was  a  going  back ♪
仿佛真能回溯往昔那般
♪ Nothing  left  behind  can  pull  me  there ♪
但身后再无事物能将我牵绊
♪ What  was  has  been  erased ♪
过往早已被抹去
♪ Yet  we’re still fighting ♪
可我们仍在奋力抗争
♪ You  can’t  blame  me  for  trying ♪
你怎能怪我竭力一试
♪ I’m  gonna  live  while  dying ♪
我要在消逝中寻得生机
♪ Planets  still  reflect  the  light ♪
行星虽无法自放光芒
♪ though  they  don’t  produce  their own. ♪
却依旧折射着璀璨微光
♪ We  still  see  them  spinning  off ♪
我们仍能看见它们旋转不息
♪ and  always  moving. ♪
永不停歇，奔赴远方
♪ As  I  see  the  Juno  rise ♪
当我看到朱诺升起
♪ Into  my  orbit ♪
进入我的轨道
♪ I  think  of  all  the  tired  eyes ♪
我念及所有疲惫的眼眸
♪ And  know, ♪
而后知晓
♪ I  already  chose  a  side ♪
我早已选定心之所向
♪ As  I  see  the  Juno  rise ♪
当我看到朱诺升起
♪ Into  my  orbit ♪
进入我的轨道
♪ I  think  of  all  the  tired  eyes ♪
我念及所有疲惫的眼眸
♪ And  know, ♪
而后知晓
♪ I  already  chose  a  side ♪
我早已选定心之所向
♪ I close my eyes and Calm descends on me ♪
我轻阖双眼，宁静漫上心间
♪ Take me with you We soar to infinity ♪
带我同行吧，共赴无垠天边
♪ We're going at the speed of light Bring me higher ♪
我们以光速向前，带我飞向更高远
♪ You lift my feet up from the ground ♪
你将我双脚，轻轻抬离地面
♪ I wish upon a shooting star that you'd make me lighter ♪
我向流星许愿，愿你让我轻如羽片
♪ And now you hit my heart With the speed of light ♪
此刻你闯入我心，速度快如光线
♪ Hear the rhythm of our heartbeat Echoing eternity ♪
听我们心跳的韵律，回荡至永恒之间
♪ We will travel a thousand light years We soar to infinity ♪
我们将穿越千光年，共赴无垠天边
♪ We're going at the speed of light Bring me higher ♪
我们以光速向前，带我飞向更高远
♪You lift my feet up from the ground ♪
你将我双脚，轻轻抬离地面
♪ I wish upon a shooting star that you'd make me lighter ♪
我向流星许愿，愿你让我轻如羽片
♪ And now you hit my heart With the speed of light ♪
此刻你闯入我心，速度快如光线
♪ We're going at the speed of light Bring me higher ♪
我们以光速向前，带我飞向更高远
♪ You lift my feet up from the ground ♪
你将我双脚，轻轻抬离地面
♪ I wish upon a shooting star that you'd make me lighter ♪
我向流星许愿，愿你让我轻如羽片
♪ And now you hit my heart With the speed of light ♪
此刻你闯入我心，速度快如光线